[Silence]
Rachel and Darren, any words for our incredible finalists?
Baker, I have absolutely loved being in the shed with you, so
I cannot wait to see what you bake in the final. It's been a
real joy to see you grow in this shed. It's been an absolute
privilege to taste your delicious cakes, and it's a real
honor to know you as people. Thank you. And since we think
you're also fabulous, we've got you all a little finale
surprise. In a twist, we're going to get you to bake all the
bakes from the past 10 weeks in just six hours. Just joking.
Your real surprise is a guest judge. And no, before you ask,
it's not Judge Judy. She hates Kate. With a career that spans
decades, this judge is one of the most beloved bakers in the
country. This judge is a true national treasure. This judge
is Bake Off Royalty. That's right, Baker. Please welcome
the exquisite, the exceptional, the glorious Maggie
Brown! Oh, my God! Wow! Oh, Maggie, we are so excited to have
you here. Oh, it's so lovely to be here. You know, the Bake Off
shed is so special to me. And the excitement of being here for
just the finale, sort of like my icing on the cake. But I can't
wait to see what you bake for us. For your final signature
bake, the judges would like you to make a high tea. You must
make three items with a mixture of savoury and sweet. There
must be six of each item, so 18 in total. And of course, they
must be worthy of a signature finale bake. Judges, any words
of advice for our finalists? I'm looking for your
creativity and your personality to shine through your
bakes. High tea is all about being petite, so I'm looking for
some light and delicate bites. My advice is have fun!
Bakers, you have three hours to make your high tea. On your
marks, get set, BAKE! Good luck, good luck, good luck, good
luck! Good morning! Have fun! Oh, my goodness, Maggie, beer
wash in the door. Definitely a surprise, but just
absolutely love it. What an honour and thrill it will be to
bake for Maggie. It's hard enough to believe that I'm here in
the shed for the finale, as it is, but to have Maggie beer here
as well, it's out of the book. Rachel and Darren have shared
with me a lot about the bakers and how good they are, so I can't
wait to actually taste their bakes. This is my chickpea,
canis basa, and you cook it like a porridge. It's the grand
finale, our three finalists are so talented. There's
really nothing in it. I want to see them all do really well
today. I've chosen flavours that are really, really true to
me and my style and my inspiration, which is my family and
where I've come from. High tea is where our bakers can get
really creative. I want to see innovative design, I want to
see texture, and something delicious to eat. I smell
parmesan, I smell delicious. I'm just getting the bata
ready for my parmesan cake. I think one of the best things to
come out of the shed is the people that you meet, these two in
particular, we've become really close. There's some
really strong friendships that will carry on beyond the
shed. Adams and Priest with inventive designs. Can I spin
the wheel? Give it a little flick and the arrow should give a
spin. In four technical wins. First position, Adam. Adam,
again. Adam! He's also enjoyed a tipple. One for the syrup,
one for me. And an out of the space. Bottoms up. Hello. Hi
Adam. Hi Adam. Hello Adam. Excuse the messy bench. Oh no, no,
I feel very at ease with the messy bench. Good. Adam's high
tea will include a speculas and frangipan tart, lemon,
myrtle and ginger biscuits, and a parmesan cake with
tomato, chilli jam and pesto. This sounds really ambitious
and also sounds very delicious. All those flavours, they
sound wonderful. Adam, the thing that I can say most of all is
look for balance. The balance of the fillings with the
pastry or the biscuit is something that I've really
improved on since I've been in the shed. I'm looking forward
to seeing what you can do. I'm so excited to have you here.
These are my hazelnut biscuits. They get sandwiched
together and they'll sit on their sides. Hi Lona. Hello
Lona. I need you to tell me all about what you're going to do.
The title of my high tea is Lona's Moorish High Tea. I have
been told that I need to bring more, more flavour, more
design, more filling. I want to show that I can be more.
Awesome. Maggie, we love more. We've always been about
more. With the help of Kat Bernard. With my sous chef. Lona's
love of vintage has shown. It's inspired by Sevenies
wallpaper. But it's her clever use of complex flavours.
Wow, fennel. Quite a powerful flavour, isn't it? That have
wowed the judges. That's really impressive. It tastes so
delicious. Week after week. So really excellent dessert.
Well done. Lona's Moorish High Tea will include hazelnut
biscuits decorated with carrot halva. It clays filled with
a chestnut cramboitisserie and chickpea panisse with
black garlic aioli. And anchovies. The concept of black
garlic and anchovy and chives, you're talking my language.
But in the anchovy, that can be overpowering. You also need
texture as well as balance. The panisse is super creamy on
the inside. But I do it in a very, very hot oven, 230, with lots
of olive oil, so it gets a crispy golden crust. I think that's
really important to have that bit of texture against that
beautiful fuziness of the black garlic. With multiple
batches on the go, the finalists must perfect the art of
multitasking. The first round may be in the oven. These are
the tart shells. It's going in the oven to blind bake. But
it's straight on to the next. This is the start of my kaya in my
miso. Kaya is a stirred coconut custard that we eat a lot for
breakfast in Singapore. This is a really big part of Asian
culture. We don't ask, you know, how are you? Or you don't
say, I love you. You say, have you eaten yet? Laura's Calypso
creations celebrate into heritage. My grandma's recipe,
she passed it on to me before she passed away, and it's like a
very important kind of responsibility that I hold. Pushing
boundaries with flavors. Wow. She took the judges along for
the ride. It's so inventive. I love how so many of your bakes
tell us a story. This is some rehydration seaweed. I'm just
going to blitz it up so that I can add it into my scones. It's
nice and fine. Laura's Vevno Place Like Home High Tea will
feature a kaya milkweed, jasmine tea biscuits with lychee
jelly, and seaweed scones topped with salmon. How are you
going to get the seaweed flavor into the scones? I'm going to
mix some cream up to make a butter, and then I'll mix it in with
some furikake and some nori as well. Furikake. That amazing
combination of umami flavors. Totally. Have you really
enjoyed being in a baker's shed? It's been absolutely the
best. I've learnt so much from Darren and Rachel and the
other bakers, so I've loved making it, and I just feel
honored to be here. Oh, that's great. Well, we've loved
tasting all your delicious creations, so it's been
fantastic. Thank you. So this is No Place Like Home, so I'm
going to have to say you're Dorothy, but then you're going to
have to tell me who's the Tin Man, Scarecrow, Am I the Wisp?
I'm the Wisp. I am Scarecrow. She went there. I went there. I
fell, Tin. Thanks, Lola. This is my shu pastry. I actually
piped it in really long lines so that I can freeze it and
precisely slice it into the exact same size. Bakers, you
have the amount of time it takes me to find my name on a seating
chart even though there's a long line behind me. You have one
hour. Ah, one hour. Time is running out for the bakers to
cook. Be good, guys. Cool. It's got a tuffle. And creative
perfect fillings. I'm just adding some lemon-merciled tea
leaves to my curd just to infuse as it cooks, and then
hopefully adds another layer of lemon to my biscuits. I'm
just preparing the black garlic mayonnaise. Ooh, sorry. I
have curd up my back. A lot of spillage is happening today.
Where did the time go? I know. I spilled oil all over the
place. That's where the time went. Hello, Lola. If you need
help in the shed, you can just go... Oh, that'll come in
handy, actually. I've loved the laugh and hugs and all the
things you've done to pick us up and keep us going. Is that an
invitation? Yes. Good hug, good button. Is this
friendship? I hope so. Oh. I'm going to check my shirt. I'm
going to shoot. This is my rough puff pastry for the Mifu. I am
happy with this. It's looking lovely and clear. Fakers, you
have the length of time that Darren can go without starting a
sentence with the words I and love. 30 minutes. You have 30
minutes. I'm just going as fast as I can and hoping for the
best. They're beautiful and fluffy, these ones. I should
get them on the plate now with all of the kutrumom that I
wanted. Just about to start assembling my bits and pieces.
Which bit is this? This is my parmesan cake. Can I offer you a
sample? It's nice that you offered it to me so I don't have to
see a one. I'm just going to go back and brag to Natalie that I
got a pinch from her. Feeling it right up so that there's no
holes. I'm feeling really accomplished. Can't quite
believe that I've done all of this in three hours. Adding
some parmesan crisp for a bit of colour and movement.
Bethes, you have ten minutes to go. The time is just flying.
I'm going to be tight. I'm just piping the curd onto my lemon
and ginger biscuits. I'm going to dream about mayonnaise.
My hands shaking. I'm going to be a little bit more relaxed.
Final touch of bacon. I'm feeling good. Everything's come
out as planned. So hopefully the tasting goes well. Ten,
nine, eight, seven, eight. Oh my gosh. Three, two, one. Step
away from the tiny, delectable thing. Congratulations.
Final signature bake. Oh my god, I got it done. Beautifully
presented. Very high tea. Very elegant. I love you've got
that exactness about every single one. We have to get into
it. We'll start with the parmesan cake first. I love the
parmesan fail. Really thin and golden. Oh, it smells so
good. The tomato is really sweet, but that end of chilli. It
is beautifully balanced. You've managed to retain that
lovely bite in the parmesan cake. So it isn't soggy. It has
that nice texture. A really delicious blend of sweet and
salty and the pesto on top. I think you've created something
that's colourful and works well. We should try the speculus
of frangiband tots. Yep. Oh wow. You've managed to capture
the lovely warmth. It works so well against that almond.
This pastry is great. It's come together beautifully. The
cream was really nice and smooth and it offsets the crunch.
Well done. Thank you. Alright, lemon and ginger biscuit. I
feel like the very obedient Labrador that doesn't get
people food. Wow. Adam, I love it. They're really bright and
fresh. I love the tang coming through that lemon and then you
get the heat of the ginger. Lemon and ginger can so easily
overtake and you've got it just perfectly. You have made a
very deceiving biscuit. It looks simple, but cappale. So
well done in creating a beautifully textured biscuit that
also packed full of flavour. It's a great start for me to come
in and see what you're made of. It's fantastic. Thank you.
Such a chic and sophisticated presentation. I love how
they're all completely identical. They actually look as
moored as I suspect they will taste. Thank you. We should
start with black garlic and anchovy panisse. The batter is
firm but not tough. And then you've got the creaminess of the
black garlic. So you've managed to get texture and balance,
which is what I'm always looking for, and flavour in Spain.
Alona, that was absolutely delicious. Chickpea batter was
something really intelligent. I love the fact that it was
unusual, but it was cooked absolutely perfectly. Love big
flavour. You get that from the aioli and of course the
anchovy on top. Carrot cake with hazelnut and the carrot,
however. I love the delicateness of the hazelnut biscuit.
The textures are really beautiful because you get that
crunch, that crumble, that creaminess, and then a little
bit of chew with the carrot. So you really created a
wonderful journey with the textures. I can't wait to try
this Mont Blanc eclair because I love choux pastry, I love
chestnut and I love chocolate. Wow, I mean, just feeling
them, you can feel they're well filled. The unsweetened
chestnut, it's just fantastic because, you know, chestnut
is so rich and it can be cloying, but it's not. Really well
done. The choux pastry, nice and crispy, and the glaze on top
is beautiful. If I had asked my favourite, I would have to go
to the bottom drawer. I would second that. The bottom one is
absolutely my favourite. I think you've discovered who
your number one fan show these are. You've presented them
beautifully. The scone with the salmon and the roe and the
furikaki looks just so moorish. Alright, we're going to
have a scone. Wow, Laura, back in London, we never had any
flavours like this with our scones. Very traditional. I
love the saltiness, I love the savouriness, the umami. It's
the perfect start to a high tea. Thank you. The salmon with
the furikaki and then the salmon roe, because they like
explode in your mouth. So you're adding like another
sensation to the person eating it. I think that's really
clever. I think it's another take on a scone and one that I
would have any day. Picky. The Jasmine Tea Biscuit next. The
biscuit is really fantastic. You've got that goldenness in
it that gives it that nice crispness. And the lychee just
lifts everything. Alright, the kaya jam milfe. That kaya
jam, it's got that pandem flavour, but also you've got a bit
of saltiness going on there, which is what you want in the
kaya jam. The pastry is beautifully flaky. It really is
good. Thank you. Laura, you always nail the flavours of
Southeast Asia. It's delicious, it works really well
together. I love the textures. Well done again. Thank you.
What I love about Sterling and Rachel is they leave no scone
unturned. Thank you so much. Thank you. I'm feeling so
relieved. That's done. It was a big task. I'm really proud of
myself that I put up something beautiful and very
delicious. I was really proud with how the bake went today.
Heading into the technical, I really hope I can keep the good
momentum going. But who knows what we've got in store with
Maggie here. I'm prepared for whatever comes my way
tomorrow. And I'm going to go in with the same positivity I
had today. Bakers. The technical bakers here for the final
time. In being the finale, it is the trickiest technical
bake known to all of humankind. This very special challenge
has been set by real life angel Maggie Beard. Maggie, any
hints for our bakers? Don't crumble under pressure. Give it
a slap. What? Be firm. That's all. Judges, it's time for you
to leave the shed so we can gossip about you behind your back.
Good luck everyone. Good luck. Good luck guys. Now that
they've gone, I can reveal to you that the judges would like
you to make Maggie Beard's Guinea Fowl Turin. Maggie's
Turin is made from a special short crust pastry with whole
wheat flour. Inside, there are six separate layers.
Panchetta, marinated Guinea Fowls, apricots, and three
very special layers traditionally called sparse. Sort of
like the sparse of me having to remember all of that. Bakers,
you have three hours to make Maggie Beard's Guinea Fowl
Turin. On your mark, get set, face! Three pages. Three. Lots
of very classic Maggie-type ingredients. So looking
forward to seeing how it all comes together, it's generally
very tasty. Our finale steak bake has been set by Maggie
Beard, which seems very surreal. It's the team, I guess,
that it's the hardest technical weapon. Here's my Guinea
Fowl Turin and red onion and kumquat mamanade. Wow! That is
amazing. Look at that crust. It's a short crust pastry, but
using wholemeal flour. Oh, there you are. How beautiful are
those layers? So we have the very finest layer of the
panchetta. Then we have the fars, then the Guinea Fowl
Brifts, and of course the dried apricots from my orchard.
And what's the fars made of? Well, the fars is made of Guinea
Fowl leg, pork belly and pork fat. If you don't get that
cohesion of the fars, it will never work, and you have to slap
it. Until it's fatty and sticky, or else it'll be crumbly.
Okay. Yes, let me give you some. Oh, thank you. I love the
colour in your marmalade. It's like bright red and orange.
So inviting. Maggie, wow. You're so naughty. Naughty?
There's lots of work in there. This is so delicious, but such
a challenge. Oh, thank you. It's so delicious. That pastry
just melts in your mouth. And then you have that contrast of
textures with the fars and the apricots and pistachios just
add that crunch and texture. The bakers are definitely
going to have a tough time doing this in three hours. But we
wanted to challenge our bakers with the very best, and I
think Maggie has absolutely brought that in space. I just
hope that they embrace it and love it. So I'm just making my
pastry at the moment, pulsing the flour and the lard
together, and we'll add the butter and sour cream and then
chuck it in the french tarette. I've never made a terrine
before. I have made a short crust with lard, so I feel that
that's something. And I'm just going to try and trust my gut.
Maggie's first clue about not crumbling under pressure is
about this pastry. Wholemeal flour tends to crumble a
little bit because it's got a lot less gluten than regular
plain flour. So it can be a bit tricky to work with. Oh! I'm
just preparing my guinea fowl breast for marination. Have
you cooked with guinea fowl before? I think that what I'm
doing right now shows you. No. I feel like this is a dish for
Bernard. Oh, he might like this, sure, yeah. Guinea fowl
breast marinade is completed with juniper and orange. Then
the most difficult step begins. Fuff. Fuff is a whipped up
meat and aromatic mixture, like a sausage mix almost that
kind of pads out the terrine. This softening the onions and
the garlic here and about to add some burgers. Maggie's fast
has no less than 17 different ingredients, including
herbs, orange rind, guinea fowl and pork fat. And to bring it
together, a cheeky technique. I am fuffing my fast. I have no
idea if I'm doing this right or how. So when we're supposed to
do it, I really have no clue. That's such an awesome record.
This is quite fun. It's also helping to manage my anxiety
right now. I feel like it's come together. Hey, what you
doing? Just flapping my fast. Why? Apparently we're doing
this until the fat can yield. Does that work on like...
Instead of going to the gym? Yes. If you just let me a number of
times, Natalie? Yeah. I'm willing to find out. Oh, gosh. I
think I've slapped the fast enough, yes. I'm going into the
fridge to chill. I'm going to get some cold. Bakers, you have
the length of time. It would take me to list 20% of Maggie
Beers' accomplishments. Two hours. You have two hours.
It's very important to get this bit right. Because the
pastry is what's holding everything together. The pastry
must be rolled and cut so the terrene assembly can begin. Why
in the basin find the pastry with pancetta? It's slightly
overlapping. This is the marinated guinea fowl breast.
It's... I think the clue, B-Firm, is about making sure that
the terrene firmly packs. It's important for the balance of
flavour, the structure of the terrene, and to make sure
you've got nice, even layers. Then I'm going on with spas and
the apricots. These apricots are straight from the
orchards of Maggie Beers, which is... Does most special
thing ever? Looks like it will fit, which is lovely. Got to
roll my lid out, John. Good touch. Arrange pastry leaves in
the centre. Can't believe I'm putting... my final tech bake
in the oven. It feels pretty good. Lovely. The terrene will
bake for up to an hour. So the bakers move on to the onion and
come quite marmalade. My favourite thing baking in the set.
I've loved every minute of this, and I don't want it to end.
Oh, my God. Cook, please. I love the colour. You can't really
control. What's happening in the oven? You've got to touch
your waist. Baker Rooves! You have 30 minutes to come up with
a better nickname than Baker Rooves! Also for your bake.
Probably concentrate on your bake. Do that one. Alright,
that's not even close. Sorry, it's going to be quite a while.
It's going to wait. It's going to wait. Take it easy. I think
you should do a sedochial or something if you've got this
kind of time. Maybe we can just do some northern crosses.
Northern crosses. Alright. It's been so long since I've
played this game. I'm going to go get some more. The bakers
must find the perfect balance between cooking and cooling.
I don't know. The temperature gauge is going up and down. The
terrain needs time to rest. Or it could crumble when coming
out of the tin. Baker, two minutes to go. You should be
getting your terrains out of the mould. Please don't fall
apart. Okay. Okay. Not long to go, Bacon. Looking pretty
good. I'm holding together. Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one. Hands off your terrains. And
well done. Bacon, could you please bring your terrains to
the table? Oh God, how do you get it? The last one. Okay,
useful. We're looking at a photo. Who will have that? For the
final time, the judges will blind taste the technical
bakes. Oh, look at them. Well, Rachel and Darren told me that
no matter how hard this was, you do it brilliantly. And I am
thrilled by what I see. So well done. They were so right. All
right, shall we start? It's so beautifully golden. It is
very neatly done. The little leaves are lovely. The
tension. It really tastes good. I'm certainly getting the
citrus, but the seasoning's not quite strong enough. The
pastry, oh, it crumbles in your mouth. Inside the fast, the
proteins have bound together, and it's a really well
constructed terrain. Unfortunately, the master of the
bakes is a little bit more caramelised, not quite as vibrant
as Maggie's. All right, let's try the next one. This
Guinness Outerene looks beautiful. Oh, it's a nice crumbly
feeling as I cut into that pastry. Wow. Beautiful layers of
the apricot, guinea fowl and the pistachio. The paste is
superb. I would have liked the marmalade cooked a little
more. There's a brightness of colour that comes from
cooking it that bit further, but all in all, another very
good job. I love the texture of the farce. They've done some
good slapping. I didn't think I'd ever say that on a baking
show before. The top is particularly neat and pretty. The
marmalade is really eye-catching, that colour. I mean,
it's almost matching. This is better than mine. This is like
a jewel. I can't wait any longer. I'm going to cut into this.
All right, all right. Go on. OK, what will it reveal? I'm
making some of the toy inside. OK, here we go, guys. Look at
that. We've done very well with the layers. It looks like the
farce is really well held together. I think it looks really
good. Well done. Fantastic onion and kankwa marmalade. The
pastry, the pie, it is so flaky and crumbly. I mean, it's
awesome what they've done here. I think the farce is really
well made, and it's cooked really, really well. Absolutely
sensational piece of work. Well, Bakers, there's almost
nothing in this. It's like trying to choose who is your
favourite child. That's how close it is. Really well done.
The judges will now rate the Bakes from first to third. In
third position. Laura, it was absolutely delicious. It was
so close, but the marmalade just let this down a little bit.
In second position. In third position. Elona. The fineness
of those layers of the pastry is so exciting, me. So thank
you. That means in first position, it's Adam. Woo!
Surprise, surprise. Mate, what's that? Five now, you've
won. I'm a little bit speechless, but really happy. I'm
proud. That farce was the hardest part of this whole dish,
and you nailed it. So well done. Thank you. I can't believe
I've won my fifth technical, but I've won a technical set by
every single judge that has come through this season. It's
literally a dream come true. I am thrilled for this. There is
nothing between us, and it really does come down to
tomorrow's showstopper. I just want to go in there and have
fun. Final ever showstopper is so crazy to me, say it like
that. I'm going to put my best foot forward, do something
that is really true to myself, and hopefully do myself
proud. Our finalists are preparing to enter the shed for one
last time. Perfect weather for nice hot cup of tea. Bake off
shines even on a rainy day. It's been a very lovely thing for
me to walk back in and just have this little glimpse of you
all. Maggie, you really put them to the test with your guinea
fowl terrine. And I take my head off to them, because if I were
given a recipe like that, I'd freak out. They're so close at
the moment. It's hardly anything in it. You're so right.
Each one of them is so talented. Adam, it's no wonder his
confidence has grown five times. He's come first in
technical. He's literally riding that technical wave.
Laura manages to think of his concept, think of a story, and
she expressed that story in her bag. What I love about Eloda
is how well she can come up with a concept and then translate
that into beautiful bags. One of the nicest things is that
everyone's become friends while they're in the shed. The
little pit talks and reassurance, it's really lovely. You
know, over the years, I've seen all the ups and downs and the
surprises, and it comes down to the showstopper. I'll tell
you what my prediction is. It's going to be either Adam,
Elona, or Laura. Oh, wow. Oh, my gosh. So beautiful. Long
ago. Good luck. I love you. Have a good time. Bacon. It's
official. It's the last ever showstopper. What that means
is Natalie and I will be eating as much leftover cake as we can
and stealing anything that's not locked down. Obviously,
I'm just kidding. By tonight, one of you will be crowned
Australia's best amateur baker. For your final
showstopper, the judges would like you to make a 3D illusion
cake. A cake designed to look like something else entirely.
This is just an excuse to make Darren feel better because he
keeps walking around eating inanimate objects going, I
thought it was cake. It was a button, Darren. We all knew it
was a button. Your showstopping illusion cake can be any
flavor, design, or style you like. So, bakers, go wild.
Judges, any hints for our bakers? Bake with joy in your heart
and a springtour, kitchen twack if you've got this. Have fun
today and use the positive energy from your last day in this
shed to produce your best bake yet. I can't tell you how
excited we all are because you're going to give us something
so brilliant that it's going to be so hard to decide between
you. So, give it all your love. Bacon, you have four hours to
bake your illusion cake showstopper. On your mark, get set,
bake! Wow, wow, my mountain of butt up. Looks ridiculous.
Today, I am making a vase of flowers, clearly inspired by
what's around the shed. This is literally the first time I
have attempted an illusion cake before. I chose
gingerbread cake because it's going to pack a punch. But
more importantly, this is quite a dense, tight clump, which
means it's really easy to carve. Oops, very much cake.
Hello, Adam. Hello. Last time. Oh, no. I loved it. Two mixes,
you know. Makes you look very professional. Yeah, I started
with one. It was a little bit too much going on, as you can see,
they're both full. So, yeah, a lot of cake today. Adam's vase
will be decorated with painted fondant and handcrafted
wafer paper flowers. Inside, a lemon and thyme cake will be
layered with blueberry compote and juniper buttercream.
Juniper in the buttercream. I love the idea for that bitter
note, so it's not super sweet. I'm going to add salt to that,
so hopefully it balances the flavours out. Who of your
friends and family are coming today? My partner, Nick. Oh,
sorry. He's a little... Thank you. Oh, come on, man. Well,
you said you wanted salt in your bag. Yeah, exactly. This is
how I'm going to balance the flavours. Oh. So much luck.
Thank you. That's a lot. Thank you. You're welcome. Oh, God.
For my illusion cake today, I'm making a little Hawker
coffee breakfast scene, which I'm calling kopitiam, which
means coffee shop in Hokkien. Laura's Hawker breakfast
will include two cups made from coffee sponge with an Irish
liqueur jelly top. Brown butter sponge eggs will be coated
in gold chocolate. The takeaway coffee bag will be made from
dark chocolate coated sponge, surrounded in rice paper,
with hazelnut liqueur jelly ice cubes. I love this idea. I
mean, it brings back memories of me going to visit my
relatives in Malaysia. I haven't seen your Hawker stall in
this style, so I need more information. They used to serve
takeaway coffees in sort of little freezer bags. Okay. And
they'd pour the coffee in the bag with the ice cubes in the
bag, and you'd walk around just the market with sipping on
your coffee. That sounds so ambitious. It works in my head.
That's how it comes together for you today. See, good. There
we go. With the tiding on the line, the bag is must whiz, whiz
and blend to create finale-worthy fillings and toppings.
I'm making a mandarin jam for my mandarin. I like the play on
the fillings being the fruit that I'm modelling. In a way, I
hope people feel like they're actually eating into the real
thing. Alona will sculpt gingerbread cake filled with jam
in the form of various fruits. Kiwi, banana and mandarin.
She will also create an onion containing gold chocolate
ganache. All the fruit will be covered in marzipan and
hand-painted. Oh, you've already made it. You're so quick,
Alona. I'm so impressed. It's amazing. It's just like the
real thing. So your flavours are all around the gingerbread
and then the fruit and the jam to give the sweetness. I hope
that there's sharpness in my jams as well, so that it's not
overly sweet. I'm choosing not to use fondant today. I'm
modelling with marzipan. It really looks organic. Good
luck. Good luck, Alona. Thank you so much. I've got an Irish
cream jelly and I have a hazelnut peculiar jelly. Very hot,
very, very, very, very, very, very, very hot. Hello. How are
you? Good. So you've made things inspired by your family.
Any of them going to be joining us? My mum will be joining us.
I'm really excited to be in the shed and to see what's been
going on. My mum thinks I make a testin on the show, so...
Lovely. My mum is very surprised I'm still here. I've got my
Swiss meringue buttercream on the way and the blueberry
compost, which is almost done. There's a lot going on at the
moment, but I think it's tracking OK. Right. Set little
jetties. Fingers! Lights your cake. Time is an illusion.
You've got to tell them how long we've got. Sorry. You're
halfway. You've got two hours to go. Oh, crap. It's going so
fast. This is my marzipan. It's just setting a little bit of
almond extract. It's super strong. We're out of the oven.
Lovely. What's the cake happening today? Good. They're
beautifully moist and fluffy, and I think they're the
perfect texture for carving. So I'm just carving up the
sections of the cake to make the bars, and that's fun. The
construction will be the tricky part. One of the most
important parts of a hawker breakfast is the soft-boiled
egg. I'm going to mash up some of this cake and make it look
like an egg yolk. I'm having fun. I actually feel like this is
my thing. There's meek and bananas out of cake, you know,
just the usual. Inside the shed, assembly is in full swing.
Maybe if I need someone to speak, I might need your help.
Outside, all of our wonderful bakers arrive to give the
finalists some much-needed support. Oh, my God. I'm going
to go into view today. How are you? Yeah. I love your work.
That's just awesome. I can't wait to see it all put together.
I should see you all. Oh, my God. Keep it up. Oh, thank you so
much. Are we in the chairs or the couch? If I get in there, I
might want to get out. Can we eat that? No. Having the
contestants back in here, it's full of energy again in the
shed, and it's really a beautiful thing. I just felt like
you've been watched. Nothing like an audience. When the
judges cut this open, I'm hoping they see some nice, clean
layers. This is one of the coffee cups. I'm just covering it
in a crumb coat at the moment. I've carved a little bit off so
that it's a little bit rounded. I'm blowing up some water
balloons. They're going to be the mould for my kiwi fruits.
I'm going to dip them in white chocolate that's been dyed
green, and then I'm going to dust them with cocoa. Elena,
that looks fantastic. I want to try it. I've never used this
much fondant before. It needs to warm up a bit. I'm just
shaping some rice paper into sort of bag shapes over these
moulds. And then I'm going to fill the little hunk of cake
with a cup of ganache to make it look like a dark coffee. I
think I'm tracking okay. I'm going to start making some
onion skins. I paint it with colour and water. And I drape it
on onion. This looks very exciting. We were hoping to get you
another cat photo. Yes. But we ran out of cat, so we had to make
one of our own. It actually exists. I think Darren was a
little like nice and some whiskers would be fabulous. I'm
going to leave it on with the onion. Good luck. Thank you.
White sneakers on a rainy day. Oh, mate. I think the best
thing about using fondant, it gives you that nice smooth
finish. This is the one that's is non-negotiable that I have
to get done. Because it's so cool. If I can get it done, it's
cool. If I can't get it done, then it's nothing. Onion skins.
So this is my take away plastic bag of coffee. And I will pop
some jelly cubes in it. Bakers! 30 minutes to go. Oh my God, 30
minutes. I've got to make as many leaves and flowers as I
possibly can. And I still need to paint the vase. You know
some aliens that way for things. Yeah, yeah. Oh, wow. With
the end in sight, the families arrive to give the finalists
some love. Oh, Lord. So proud of you. Hi, P. Hi, P. Would you
like to take a picture with me? Shut it off, I'll take a
picture. Okay, where am I? Oh, the race is finished. We'll
show it to you. I've got one onion skin left to patch on.
Hopefully it looks sort of like an onion. This is the first
time I've painted fondant like this. Bakers! You have 10
minutes to go. Oh my gosh, it takes days and hours. Samora!
I've got a lot to do. Samora! Samora! I'm happy with it. I have
the desire as well. Bakers! One minute left. You think of
what makes the last laugh. Oh my God. 10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2,
1. Yes! Adam, can you come to the front, please? Tell us what
you've made for us. I've made a vase of flowers. And so the
cake is a lemon and time cake filled with blueberry compote,
roasted salted almond, and a Swiss meringue buttercream
with juniper. It looks so pretty. I love it. I love how all the
petals have been beautifully painted. I love your vase. I
love the scale of it, the symmetry of it, and I can't wait to
taste it. There's been a lot of work gone into that. It looks
pretty amazing. I love that bright, vibrant purple from the
blueberries. It really looks appetising. Thank you. Adam,
that is absolutely delicious, mate. Really tangy lemon
sponge. The buttercream, it's really cleverly done
because it's very easy to overpower the juniper and it can
become quite bitter. For me, it's a little bit simple, but
sometimes simple is the best. I was worried about the
sweetness, but you've managed to retain a lovely tartness
in the blueberry and the lemon syrup. That's really well
balanced. The cake I love. I love citrus, and I love that it's
moist, and I love the juniper. I would have put more juniper
in, but it is such a lovely cake. Thank you, thank you. Thank
you. Ilona, please come up. My showstopper is a fruit and
vegetable still life. You certainly have created a still
life. Those bananas, they look like they're ready for some
banana bread. There is a gingerbread cake. The bananas have
banana spread filling. The kiwis have a kiwi jam filling.
Wow, it looks really fun. The mandarin has a mandarin jam
filling, and the onion is filled with ganache. So this is the
banana filling. The cake has this lovely warmth and a really
nice bite to it, which I like in a gingerbread. I love the
mother pen and the banana flavor with that soft spice. So I
think you've done well. Kiwi next. I love that kiwi fruit
jam. So bright, so vibrant, and it's so delicious. It's just
so delicious. It's just so fragrant, and really it's just a
fresh flavor. Gingerbread with the kiwi, unusual
combination, but it worked very well. OK, let's try the
mandarin. It's not as realistic as your other fruit. Ilona,
do you know what it's just missing? It's taking a toothpick
and adding those little dimples, but it's beautiful. The
ginger is more dominant, and there's that lasting citrus in
the back palate that is so lovely. Gingerbread with
mandarin is such a good combination, because it really
works. Come on, let's do the onion. I'm going to do the raw
onion though. I've got some tissues if you start crying,
Darren. I've gone over the last time. Wow, what a
cross-section. She's got the guava, the mandarin, the cold
chocolate ganache going through the middle, which looks
really great. It looks like proper onion skin. It really
does. It's fabulous. This is so clever. The caramel notes
bring out that lovely gingerbread warmth. It's a delicious
combination. I'm not surprised you used that ginger cake
throughout, because it was absolutely delicious. The
presentation was absolutely spectacular, something an
old master would be proud to paint. Very well done. Thank you
very much. Thank you very much. Laura, please come up to the
table. This is gobekyang breakfast, which means hawker
coffee shop breakfast. You have two cups of coffee sponge
and a coffee buttercream. There's a jelly on top. Yes, it's
an Irish coffee jelly. All of those layers, but it's so much
fun. The soft-boiled eggs, a vanilla brown butter sponge
with the same buttercream, and the takeaway coffee bag is
coffee cake with dark chocolate. This brings back memories
for me going to see my relatives in Singapore and Malaysia. I
just love how you captured it. Fantastic job. Thank you. I
think we should try the coffee bag. Plastic. Isn't it
amazing? It's clever. The hazelnut liquor jelly goes so
well with the chocolate and then the coffee. The sponge is
really more-ish. It looks spectacular, and from now on, I'm
calling down all my drinks with hazelnut liquor. All right,
egg next. Oh, it's got a crispy shell on the outside. Oh, wow,
look at that. It's even got a little yolk. That is so cool. The
sponge has a wonderful texture and has that lovely caramel
note, and I love that you put an egg yolk in there. Again, just
fantastic attention to detail. It's not easy getting that
yolk in the center, you know? So congratulations on that.
The only way you could have possibly improved on that is if
you'd put, like, a little liquid center in there. So when we
cut through, that would have been really awesome. I love the
whimsy of this, and I see it as a hard-boiled egg that you've
cooked perfectly. So the center is sitting there. I think a
cup of coffee next. Yeah, absolutely. That crunch of the
praline with the lovely coffee flavor, it's fantastic,
thank you. Out of all the cakes, I think this is the one you've
nailed, the flavors, the textures, and the visual. Thank
you. I love the little bubbles on top of the jelly. It's just
giving that effect of freshly-frost coffee. I absolutely
love this, and it's my favorite of all of the things that
you've made on this board today. So really well done. Thank
you. Bakers, well done. Those illusion cakes were
sensational. We really love the visuals, and we love the
flavors. It's going to be so difficult for us to make a
decision. Absolutely incredible job. Well done. Looks
really good. Oh, poor. Good job. It is so good. I just have to
come and give you a hug. Congratulations, Mrs. Coulomb. Oh,
would she have thought? Thanks, happy finale. Yay! What a
night. And it's so exciting that we're allowed in the
grown-up's area as well for the first time. It's very nice
here, I like it. We've had such a magical week. We really have
been impressed by all of the three finalists. And to have
Maggie back as well has just been icing on the cake. This is
your first year in a Bake Off ship. Has it been everything you
thought it might be? It's been a dream. So good. For me
personally, it's been an absolute dream come true. And I
feel so lucky and blessed. The energy, like, there's just
the positive energy and the warmth. And you feel like it's a
little family. Well, that is the Bake Off magic. And I had
five years of it, and I'm so proud that you are sitting around
here loving it as much as I did. Thanks, Maggie. I think we're
in an impossible pickle because we have to make a hard
decision on... It's going to be crowned the greatest
Australian amateur baker. All of our finalists have been
star baker twice. So this is neck and neck. This is a very
tight competition. How did Adam go? Enjoy. Oh, my God. Adam
with his beautiful vase and delicate flowers, he really
captured that horse's name look. The blueberry offset with
the lemon, it tasted absolutely amazing. But the juniper in
the cream just needed a bit more of a punch and a bit of gin, and
I would have been even happier. Mmm. It's so amazing. Yeah, I
love this. It's definitely a winning bake. And what about a
loner? She has got a very distinctive style. She's been so
elegant, and her work has been so precise. In her
showstoppers, each one of those cakes were amazing. The
onion got me more than anything else. It was so fantastic.
Yay! I am so impressed, and I'm so proud of you. Thanks, Mum.
It's true. Loz's showstopper really did evoke a story, and
she's been doing that the whole way through. I really think
she captured that feel you get from going to a coffee shop in
Singapore. I was just blown away by her attention to detail.
That plastic coffee with the straw and the ice. Yeah. I think
she's special, like all of them. The truth really is that
we've got three winners in there already. That's great, but
like, who is the winner? Are you going to... Keep the
attention going. Final cheers. I love you all. Cheers.
BAKERS. Well done on making it all the way to the finale. It is
such a huge achievement. It's been so great to have the
chance to come back to the shed and see you all shine. Each one
of you deserves to be here. Adam, Laura, Ilona. Every week
you've reached new heights, and this is no exception. I want
you all to leave this shed knowing each of you are brilliant
bakers. Guys, I absolutely love it here, and I absolutely
love each one of you. Just sharing in your stories of food and
your love of baking has been a real, real pleasure for me.
Thank you very much. OK. Deep breath. Yes. It's finally
here, the moment we've been waiting ten weeks for. It is my
extraordinary pleasure to announce that the winner of the
Great Australian Bake-Off is... Laura. CHEERING AND
APPLAUSE I knew it. Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Congratulations. That's just one, the Great Australian
Bake-Off. What's just saying that sounds ridiculous, like
so crazy? I'm in shock. This is a complete dream come true, to
be able to bring the title home and to do it with my mum in the
room. Oh, my God! My God! I've just learnt so much from this
whole experience. I've had the absolute time of my life.
Congratulations! Thank you so much. Laura. Thank you,
Laura. So pleased for Laura, a proper, worthy winner. She's
been consistent throughout, and she's got better every
week, and her bakes are delicious. APPLAUSE The bakers are
so amazing. Obviously, there has to be a winner, but I'm
really proud of all the finalists. They have achieved some
amazing bakes in the shed, and it's been wonderful to see how
they've grown as well. Come. Thank you. This whole
experience has been more than I could have possibly
imagined, and I leave with more confidence in myself, which
I think is the greatest gift the shed has given me. Oh, Elona!
Oh! So amazing. I may not have won overall, but I do feel like
I've won so much. I have grown and become stronger, not just
my baking, but in my belief in myself that I can do anything. I
think that's a really important thing for me to remember and
to take away with me. APPLAUSE Marking. And show all the
cameras. There you go. Thanks, man. Train come through. I'm
feeling it. Oh, I'm feeling it. Ooh. Ooh. Oh, I'm OK. Oh! Oh,
my God! That killed Rachel, too. It won't be too thick. Oh,
sorry. Oh! It was near when I had longer hair. Are you ready,
Tobine? I'll give you the good crack. Oh! That was awesome.
That's he from Kate. Whoo!