[Silence]
It's party week today! Come on, Paul, let's do the conga. I am
buzzing. BOOING Tom was so excited when I said it was party
week. He's been hoping for this theme for years. Vote for the
Tom Allen party, Tom Allen for Prime Minister! Eventually,
vote for the Tom Allen party, everyone! Oh, that's sort of
party. I knew it was too good to be true. I'll vote for Tom.
Thanks, Pistone. Prime Minister's vote! CHEERING
CHEERING Hello and welcome. It was party week in the tent.
Something never attempted before, and Prue knew there was
only one way to get through it. Nice nose. Prue! Come on. Come
on, let's go. Put the bottle. I know. I know. I'm so sorry.
Josh was every eight-year-old at a party after too much
sugar. Just down to kind of coke in about a minute. And it's
just time for the latest instalment of Who Knew with Prue.
Some trees are bisexual. They're male and female on the same
tree. And... And a reminder that you can watch the rest of
that episode on Channel 4 Catch Up. Tom will be back later to
inspect the party food. Who's helped with the catering?
CHEERING And, of course, we love having a peek at what you've
been baking in your kitchens at home. Like Anne from Lithams
and Anne's, who wanted to show off the cake she made for her
husband, Stephen's 70th birthday. Stephen's a keen tennis
player, and here's his cake. Clearly, Stephen has just
completed a particularly exhausting five-setter there.
But game-setting match to you, Anne. Brilliant. There'll
be more of those later, along with details of where to send
your pictures. Now, sadly, the party's over for one of the
bakers, Christie. Oh! During party week, Christie really
let her hair down and said something so shocking she
couldn't even believe it herself. I like sausage rolls. I
like sausage rolls as well, Christie. Something we can
discuss in a lot more detail when she's here later in the
show. To help us raise a toast to party week, I've invited a
fantastic panel of celebrity Bake Off fans. Present us,
Carla Moffitt, Camille Nabil Abou-Washid and Camille and
actress and writer, Ashring B. Now, Carla, just lovely to
have you with us. If you're hosting a party, what's on the
menu? Anything that's in the whoop-sile. Fucking going
there. Just anything, be it sausage rolls, Scotch eggs,
pork pies, paste pudding, breadsticks, sandwiches. Just
like, you know... That sounds like a snack. What about you,
Ashring? I like when someone tricks me. Like, there's a
whole dinner but small. Like, at Yorkshire putting with a
whole dinner in it. You know, those little ones. Or like a
little sausage roll or like a thimble of magic mushrooms or
something. You know, just party quick. Buffet things that
you're nibbling on. Nabil, what food do you want to see on a
buffet table? I mean, I like things like Scotch eggs. Only
enough for a lot of these desserts. I grew up in Nigeria and
saw a lot of our desserts and a lot of our pastry-type stuff is
very Scottish. So, like, we like sausage rolls, Scotch
eggs. Very, very, very popular in Nigeria. Anything dipped
in lard? Yeah. Me too. That's the results. Ditto. OK, well,
let's remind ourselves what happened when Bake Off had a
bash. The quarterfinal. BEEPS And time to get the party
started. With Paul's all-time favourite. Sausage rolls.
Soy sauce, ginger, garlic. In the signature. Anything's a
louding pace, for sure. But not a sausage roll! Matty turned
up the heat. Nice bit of kick there from the chilli. A bit of
chilli flakes, yeah. And earned himself a handshake. Aw!
Thank you for bringing me a sausage roll. Caterpillar cakes
in the technical. Oh, yeah. What anything but child's play.
In the first spot, we have this one. Tasia. Beige was banned.
She didn't rise. In the colourful, all you can bake buffet
showstopper. Josh, I think you've done really well. It's
hard to fault anything. Sadly, the party was over for
Christy. It's a bit rough and ready. Oh, no. It tastes great.
And she left the tent. And Matty's sporty bake...
Cricketball pies. That's delicious. ...scored him his
second star baker. APPLAUSE So, the signature challenge
was to make Paul's all-time top treat, sausage rolls. Now,
Bill, you quite like a bit of cooking, don't you? But can you
make pastry? No, OK, here's the thing. Like I said,
culturally, we were told that cooking was OK for guys, but
only girls bake. Oh! Yeah, I know. So, currently, I'm
learning to bake from my daughters. Yeah, I'm trying to, you
know, reverse all the toxic masculinity, which is almost as
bad as gluten. LAUGHTER Well, this might surprise you, but I
can make the sausage roll. Just push it down a hill. Ay!
APPLAUSE What a lovely smatter of applause. Thank you so
much. On to Dan. Last week, he stunned the judges by serving
up Thai green curry creme caramel that sounded disgusting,
but tasted delicious. This week, it was dim sum-inspired
sausage rolls. Sadly, the judges didn't go for his
Chinese-inspired pork and prawn fillings. Well, I'll be
totally honest. I might sound thickier, but I didn't know
you could put stuff other than sausages in sausage rolls. Do
you know what I mean? The poll would be like, You can't! Well,
yeah, because I just thought a sausage roll was just like a
big old sausage and some pastry. It is! I mean, what
qualifies a sausage roll if there's no sausage in it? Well,
it's the big thoughts here that we're dealing with. But,
like, yeah, sticking prawns in that in. Oh, I don't know how I
feel about that. I just think we need to stick to the basics. A
sausage roll should have some form of rolling. That was done
to a sausage of some kind. I mean, if we don't hold on to this, I
don't know where we're going as a society. But I loved that
something different was tried, that they threw a prawn into
a sausage roll thing. And also, the show demands it. Now they
expect, like, you know, glass-aid bombs inside of cakes
that can, you know, connect to at least 3G of internet. And
so, you can listen to the email on them. Like, the
expectations are high, so, you know, give it a good whirl,
I'd say. Paul made quite a claim. You can't beat a good
sausage roll. I grew up with sausage rolls. I baked millions
and millions of sausage rolls in my time. I decided to work
out just how long it would take to bake millions and millions
of sausage rolls. Allowing for generous time to make the
pastry and filling, then bake them for 30 minutes in batches
of 12. Even if you only made one million and did nothing else
for eight hours a day, that's 45,000 days, which is over 124
years. Unfortunately, Tasha and Christie got distracted
from the task in hand when they discovered that they could
see each other through their ovens. LAUGHTER Ours are fun.
Now, Matty stayed classic with his sausage rolls. Pork,
onion, apple, oh, and one other ingredient. Where are the
chilli going? Up my arse, pru. Where's your... LAUGHTER In
the sausage meat, obviously. Matty triumphed in the
sausage roll signature because what did his flaky pastry
have, everyone? LAMINATION! Of course, lamination! Now,
here's the moment. Paul decided Matty was his man of the
match. Oh, nice crisp. Nice bit of kick there from the
chilli. Little bit of chilli flakes, yeah. Ah! Thank you for
bringing me sausage rolls. Very good sauce. It's
delicious. The onions really work, the apple really works.
The chilli is great in there. It's really good. Thank you,
Matty. Congrats to Matty on his Hollywood handshake!
APPLAUSE I'm still thrown by the fact that everyone said
lamination and we just had to pretend like it was normal.
LAUGHTER Lamination! OK, I'll just go on with my life now.
Scarlet, were you happy to see Matty get a handshake? Yeah,
like, his little eyes lit up and, like, yes, I know that, he
did a simple sausage roll, but, like, his bottom was hard,
his pastry was flaky. LAUGHTER He'd add lamination. He'd
add all the elements you need, didn't he? The tricky
technical challenge was to make an all-too-familiar
caterpillar cake, but that wasn't so familiar that Bake Off
got sued by a large supermarket chain. LAUGHTER Over to
Prue. So, Paul, the famous caterpillar cake. The trick
is... Not to infringe copyright. LAUGHTER The trick is
getting the bake right. Oh, OK, fair enough. Prue and Paul
were a bit ying and yang about the challenge. It's a terrific
challenge. It's a Swiss roll sponge. LAUGHTER I think the
caterpillar cake is a great way of going, I am friends with
you and I care about you and your birthday, but, like, within
office working hours. LAUGHTER It's obviously quite a
political cake because there are the lawsuits between
Colin and Cuthbert, but I have a bit of showbiz gossip that
after the lawsuits, they got together. And they had a little
larvae cupcake. LAUGHTER It was just a little cake.
LAUGHTER Now, the instructions demanded that the baker's
cup bits out of their Swiss roll sponge to achieve the
required shape. Then it was time for the bakers to give their
caterpillar cakes a face full of childish appeal. Enjoy
yourselves, kiddy winks. The decorations is where they can
have a little bit of their artistic flair. All kids love that
at the birthday party. I am going to do the face. I'm going to
let it set and then put its little features on. Rosie Cheeks
may look quite nice. This will be the best bit of the whole
cake, I think. It's supposed to be a little cuter. It's a bit
weird. It's not quite the children's party I was hoping for.
WHISTLE BLOWS WHISTLE BLOWS WHISTLE BLOWS WHISTLE BLOWS
LAUGHTER This is wow! Joe! You're acting. Go to the
Lattricks. After award-winning. Wow. I think my favourite
there was Matties, because nothing says fun children's
party cake like a caterpillar that's had its mouth stitched
up. LAUGHTER It looked like a new character in Thomas the
Tank engine. Thomas the cheery one, Gordon the boasty one
and Simon the serial killer. LAUGHTER Did any of those
appeal to you? The faces on them. No. No. OK. Time now to ask
the big question. What's that? That was, in fact, the dough
for Tasha's bread milk pigs. Of course it was. They formed
part of her ambitious farmyard themed buffet. There were so
many elements to her showstopper that Mattie was wondering
just how long Tasha would be stood there listing them. I've
made milk bread, pigs and blackberry creme de creme that
show and pistachio and raspberry flavoured Viennese rolls
with a raspberry and peach jam. LAUGHTER In happier news for
the second time this series, Mattie was awarded star baker.
Congratulations to Mattie! Yay! Mattie was pulling out all
the stops with his sporting themed buffet showstopper.
We've got a cricket ball curry pie, a orange cupcake golf
course and some creme brulee donut basketballs. Until now,
the question, what's that spongy orange lump doing on a golf
course has only been asked when Donald Trump's playing 18
holes at Mar-a-Dame. APPLAUSE Josh's impressive
showstopper made the battle for star baker a close race. Was
Mattie the right choice? I mean, I'm not going to take it away
from him because he did amazing, but that Christmas
showstopper... Sounds like you're taking it away from him
there, Ed. I'm sorry! But those little snowmen macaroons,
like, I would pay for them. And let's have an extra burst of
celebration to mark the fact that thanks to Mattie, we saw
the first appearance in the tent this series of a deep fat
fryer. APPLAUSE Thanks, guys. And after the break, Tom
Allen will be here with his big paper plate to sample the
buffet provided by our audience bakers. Back in a bit.
APPLAUSE APPLAUSE Welcome back. I'm here with Bake Off Fan
Scarlet Moffat, Nabil Abdul Rashid and Ashing Bee. Time now
for the party to really get started. It's Tom's tent talk!
APPLAUSE APPLAUSE Oh, hi, everyone. Hi. Hi. Sorry, we've
been having such a party backstage. Hi. Hi. How are you
doing? Oh, the party's in full swing back there. Do you want
any of these? Oh, don't worry about this. Oh, yes, we've had
all your normal party foods, yes. You know, the classics,
brulee doughnuts, courant reeds, bread, pigs. Yes, this
week it was party week. I enjoyed the no beige theme. It meant
we got to see so many colours like Christie's marvellous
sweet factory. Oh, no, that one's beige. Maybe there's
another one. How about Josh's courant? Oh, no, that was
beige as well. OK. How about Tasha's creme diplomat sheep?
Oh, OK, also beige. Gosh, baking things in the oven really
puts the beige back in, doesn't it? Oh, well, never mind.
I'll be honest. I don't know if this is a party I really want to
go to. It's all got a bit less friendly in the tent lately.
Remember when they used to all hold hands at the end? Now look
at them. Have they all fallen out? Is it getting too
competitive? Or is it the fact that guys have outnumbered
the girls now? And they're all a bit too macho for that.
Mattie's even sitting like he's in a football team photo.
And speaking of lads, lads, lads, down by the scene on his
baking secrets. So what I'll do is look at my children, copy
what someone else is doing. Ha-ha-ha! Ah! Ha-ha-ha! It
turns out that Dan is just a copycat and feels nothing but
disdain towards his fellow man. So after all that, it turns
out Dan... I actually quite like you. But that's the new
macho tent, isn't it? Just full of men who struggle to show
affection for each other. Look at the way Paul talks about
the bakers. Well, let's have a look at these pigs. Well, I
suppose that must mean he loves them. Anyway, I'd better get
back to this party. Someone's got the karaoke machine out
and the neighbours have called the police. Turn it down,
Prue, for goodness sake. Anyway, see you next week. Prue,
get that community support officer out of a headlock. I've
told you! Thanks, Tom. Right, let's take a look at some of the
pictures you've been sending in of the baking you've been
doing at home. Emma Inhove wanted to celebrate her daughter
Frieda's 10th birthday in style. Not the easiest
challenge, given that Frieda had requested a
ferret-themed party. But Emma gave it her best shot and
here's Frieda's cake. Oh, God. Emma also arranged for a real
ferret to put in an appearance, and here's the moment the two
ferrets met. Oh, my God. That is a horror picture. All of
that. Even the ferrets, like, what the hell is that? When it
comes to creating a birthday cake for her granddaughter
Matilda, Deborah in Somerset's not one to chicken out. Oh,
wow. That is great, isn't it? It's a chocolate cake with
individually handmade fondant feathers. Meanwhile, in
Middlesex, Natalie was hard at work creating a cake for the
family dog Hazel's second birthday. Aw. Just look at that
intelligent little face. Let's find out how successfully
Natalie captured Hazel in cake form. Those delicate
features of sportour, aren't they? Happy birthday, Hazel.
And finally to Kersti in Kent, who's an A-level sociology
student. She decided to put her baking skills to the test
with a recreation of none other than German philosopher
Karl Marx. But somewhere along the line, Karl Marx seems to
have morphed into Paul Hollywood. Nevertheless, dust is
capital, Kersti. Well done. Thank you for Tom to
interrogate our studio audience on the bake they brought
along. Don't let her worry. Over to you, Tom. Thanks, Joe.
Well, first up, I've got Nicky. Where's Nicky? Oh, Nicky,
right here. Hello. Hello, Nicky. Hello. Who are you here
with? James. Hi. You look familiar. Do I? Are you me? Yes, I
think you are. Nicky, how do you know this man? We work
together. Where do you work? At an auction house. Well, it
must be a posh one. You seem very posh. No, thank you. So you
work together at an auction house. I do. What do you do in the
auction house? I'm behind the scenes. Marketing.
Marketing, that sort of thing. And what do you do, James? I
mean, I sell oil paintings, watercolours, prints. OK,
you're an auctioneer? Yeah, I'm an auctioneer. Have you
been on Flog It? No, I haven't, but I know most of the people
who have. Well, why haven't you been on it, James? I've got
pride. You do seem a lot like me, James. OK, well, Nicky and
James, what have you brought along here? So that's meant to
be yourself. So you're auctioning off the missing
raspberry. That's a raspberry, is it? That is, yes. The
raspberry that's bigger than my head. Yes, that's great. I
see, I see. Lovely, lovely. You've got Noel, Alison, Paul
and Pro. Oh, wonderful. Gosh, yes, what lovely hair they all
have. No, Joe Brown, though. No, Joe Brown. Yeah, I didn't
have time. Oh, that's charming, isn't it? Oh, what I will say
is, are all the Bake Off people, are they in some sort of
quicksand while they're bidding? They're simply
disappearing into it. They're in a snowstorm, but they
still kept bidding on that raspberry. Lovely, lovely. Your
mum was meant to come. Your mum was meant to come. Yeah, she's
ill. She's ill? Oh, no. Is she OK? What's wrong with her? She
made you. She made me. Yes. Like my own mother. And... Well
done, Nicky, well done, James. Lovely to see you and lovely
to know what I'd look like wearing glasses. Thank you very
much. Now, I've got Chloe with Chloe. Hello, Chloe. Chloe.
Chloe, hi, Chloe. Who are you here with today? I'm with my
husband Bradley. Husband Bradley. I'm with my friend
Gemma. Gemma, hi. Now, Chloe, what have you done here? We've
made a chocolate cake in the shape of a yurt. Oh, a yurt? A
yurt. Which is like a fancy tent, isn't it? Yeah, it is. When
you go glamping. When you go glamping. That's glamorous
camping, isn't it? It is. Yes, that's something that people
describe me as, actually. LAUGHTER And it's got avocado
chocolate ganache. Really? Avocado? Why avocado? Because
we're vegan. Oh, I knew you'd let us know eventually.
LAUGHTER Oh, vegans can't keep it hidden, can they? No,
people know. You're vegan. You're vegan. Come in here.
You're vegan cake and you're both vegan. Yes. Lovely to be
you, vegan. I'm vegetarian. Vegetarian milkless cows.
Woo! LAUGHTER So, why is this important to you, the yurt and
everything? We love going glamping and on holiday. We go
with our friends. What do you like about glamping so much?
It's more adventurous than a hotel, isn't it? Well, is it?
It's a tent that has a bed in it. And you have to wear wellies to
go to the toilet. That's exciting. Which you don't have to
do. You don't know the hotels I stay in. And so you like the
fact you have to wear wellies to go to the toilet. OK, and do
you like going to these places as well? I quite enjoy it. You
quite enjoy it. And that's what you do for a holiday. You just
quite enjoy it? Yeah. Bradley, what do you do for a living? I
work in tech support. And... OK, thanks, Chloe. Give it up
for Chloe and Anne, Bradley and Gemma. OK, where's Crystal?
Crystal, Crystal. Over here. Crystal. Crystal. Hello. And
Emma. Emma and... Becky. Becky. We co-founded a group
called Mothers Rise Up. Mothers Rise Up, what's that all
about? It's about bread? No, we're mums, and we're rising up
for climate action. Oh, that's very impressive. Mums
rising up for climate action. One person clap. And so... Oh,
four people clap. More people clap! And so we decided to take
two, bring along, like, good clean energy to your party. So,
like this, and shredded wheat. There's a solar panel there.
There's a solar panel. Lovely. And they're powering a huge
lightbulb. And you came on public transport? I walked. You
walked? From where? I set off about three days ago. You
said... No, you didn't. Very important message. How did you
get here? I actually came by car. You came by car. Was it an
electric car? No. OK, anyway, so... No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no. Our message is that you don't have to be
pure to make statement about climate. I think that's very
important. A very important way to address it as well, I
appreciate it. So, well done, all of you. Thank you so much
for coming along today. Thank you. Which ever mode of
transport you used. How did you get here? Private jet. Tube.
All right, thanks. OK, well done. Crystal and friends,
thank you. Thank you very much. Lovely. OK, now I've got
Miles and Gary. Miles and Miles and Gary. Miles and Gary.
Gays. Yes. Gays! Gay Bakers, everyone. Always a winner. And
you two are together. Yes, we are. Yes, we are married. You
are married. Very good. OK, great. Sorry, no claps, we're
not American. Miles, where are you from? Originally from
Buckinghamshire. You're from Buckinghamshire. But we
live in Newcastle. Oh, you live in Newcastle? Yeah! How did
you meet? We met on a course when we were training to be head
teachers. You're head teachers? You were. You were head
teachers. Why did you stop being head teachers? Were you
sacked? No. No. We decided we wanted to do something
different, so we set up our own business. Oh, what does that
do? We work with schools, helping them to improve, and we do
big, choral events with lots of children. Oh, wow! In the
North East. Do you sing? We sing in a couple of choirs, do you?
Do you? Do you? I conduct a choir. You conduct a choir? Yes.
And this space? Oh, yes, the cake. Sorry, I was coming onto
the cake, Miles. Sorry, I'm not in assembly at the moment.
Yes, we can talk about the cake you made here. Now, what is it,
Miles? It's a fully inclusive choir. I was going to say
inclusive of what? Because there seem to be some
interesting characters. Different skin tones of shoe bun.
That's very important. Yes, representation. A rainbow. A
rainbow. It's a lot of bottles of champagne, so there's
drunks as well. And it's based a little bit on... We have a big
bauble party every year. Gary, what are you talking about?
So, Gary goes mad at Christmas. I go mad at Christmas and I
love Christmas trees. And so, people come round from miles
around to see your baubles? Absolutely. You can't put them
on the tree. We have lots of trees. Oh, you're those sorts of
gays. How many trees do you have? Eleven. Eleven Christmas
trees. Of different sizes. Sure, no-one likes a size queen.
No. Gary does it all. Gary does all the... I do it all. You're
not allowed near it, Miles. No, he isn't. I've never hung a
single bauble. Really? That surprises me about you. Well,
I'll take these up to the panel. I'm sure they'll enjoy them
very much. OK, welcome, everyone. Give it up for Gary and
Miles. Gary and Miles, thank you. Thank you. Oh, you are
welcome. Thank you. Wow. And I'm delighted to announce that
this week's star baker is... Chrisso, Emma and Becky.
Wonderful. Wonderful. Very important. Talk about climate
change today. Beautiful. But now I have to look sad whilst
carrying out the secretly enjoyable task of announcing who
will be asked to leave the studio this week. And I'm
afraid... It's going to be... Nicky and James, because
James is so snooty about flogging. Don't write that. Don't
write that sort of behaviour here. It's going to be James.
Great cake, though. Great cake. I hope those people get out
of that quicksand. But the good news is they each leave with a
party bag containing an extra slice of wooden spoon. And a
huge thank you to all of our studio bakers. APPLAUSE Great.
Thanks very much, Tom. Coming up after the break, star of the
party, Christy will be here. Back shortly. APPLAUSE
Welcome back. I'm here with party animals Scarlett,
Neville and Ashling. And it's time to meet the woman of the
hour. Will you please give it up for Bake Off Quarter
Finalist? Christy! APPLAUSE Welcome, Christy. Fantastic
to have you here. Thank you. First of all, massive
congratulations for making it all the way through to the
quarter final. It's a brilliant achievement, isn't it?
Yeah. It's such a good achievement for me. Having the four
kids and stuff. It's the first sort of thing I've done for
myself. And, yeah... Did they watch the show almost like a
football match? Like, I'm like, come on, Mum! Mum, can you
get me a snack? Well, you seem like a very close bunch this
year, but you bonded with one person in particular, and
you've actually brought him along tonight. Where are you?
Amos. Hello. APPLAUSE Did you two meet before the tent? Yes,
we actually met in auditions. Oh, really? It was love at
first sight. It was. When we went for the first episode, I got
out the car and, literally, Amos had just got out of his car,
and we were, like, screaming. I don't know. I'm so excited.
And we walked in together. Yeah, it was just a pleasure. It's
so nice. Have a sort of pre-friend, isn't it? Are you proud of
Christy making it so far? I am so proud of you, seriously. Oh.
But, like in the audition, I saw her cake in the audition, and
I was shaking in my boots, seriously, guys. Was it that bad?
No. It was that good. Thank you for coming along, Amos. It's
lovely to see you again. It really is. Thank you. Yeah!
APPLAUSE So, Christy, when people recognise you out and
about, what sort of thing do they say to you? Do you know what?
It's always the same, and it's always, Is Alison as lovely?
She seems on the TV in real life. Have you told everyone she's
a real cow? LAUGHTER I'm your puss, too, cos we all know she's
lovely. I'm just like, no, she's even lovely, and,
honestly, she is. She's so warm. Yeah, she's very natural,
isn't she? Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. Now, it also turns out
that you and the makers are always talking about no. Watch
this. You do have great skin, though, I must say. We always
talk about it. He does. I think the reason I said that is
because that was the week we all found out he turned 50. No
way! What? He's 50? Wait, or 40? No, he's 50, yeah. No, he's
50. So, how did you get on with Paul and Prue? Yeah, when I
first met Paul... LAUGHTER That wasn't his! Yeah, Paul
scared me more than Prue. Prue seemed more soft. Yeah, she's
lovely. Paul's lovely, too. I think as the weeks go by and you
get to know them, you just feel much more relaxed and at ease,
and you're sort of talking to them outside of judging. But
during judging, Paul's pretty brutal. Yeah, I think he
likes to think that he's intimidating, doesn't he? Yeah, he
definitely plays on it, yeah. But because I must say, I'm
really enjoying watching you and Paul on your spin-off
show, Alien Autopsy. MUSIC PLAYS That was the dreaded
eight-plated bread, of course. Yeah. Panna, would you
watch a crime drama with Paul as the maverick cop and... He'd
be called something like the needy detective. I'd like him
to be called the Killsbury Doughboy. LAUGHTER And then you
could have Alison as the death sardine. There's been a
murder! Ha-ha! LAUGHTER Right. Well, let's revisit some of
your incredible creations, because they were. Now, in
Botanical's week, the judges couldn't resist your maple
and pecan spice buns, and you won the lemon and thyme drizzle
cake technical. And then you seem to really enjoy the whole
experience of making your floral dessert showstopper.
Well, you might not be... Let's just have a look at that and
listen to what your thoughts were on that challenge. Oh,
thank God it's over. LAUGHTER Yeah. Yeah, you did your fail,
like, yeah, absolutely. You kicked off pastry week by
getting a Hollywood handshake for your creamy,
leek-and-mushroom picnic pies and dazzled the judges with
your autumnal lattice pies, which earned you star baker.
Yeah. How was that? APPLAUSE It was amazing. I didn't expect
it. You know, you're very modest. You don't want to get your
hopes up. Of course, Josh was amazing, and in my mind, it was
100% going to him. So when they say your name, it was just
like, yeah, it's such a nice experience, really lovely. And
some of your most memorable bakes included your chocolate
week showstopper, which looked exquisite. And, of course,
your incredible cake week showstopper. In the guise of a
duck, look at that, everyone. That is the main thing. I think
it's a duck. A real duck. APPLAUSE Here's a bit of that unseen
footage from Bread Week, which made me laugh. I don't really
know how it's gone. How has it gone? OK. Yeah, it's gone quite
well. LAUGHTER That's it. They just do it as I'm told.
Absolutely. That's so sweet, though. So, for now,
everybody, thank you so much. Christy. CHEERING AND
APPLAUSE So, what does every good party week need? Music.
Well said. That's brilliant. LAUGHTER Very well done. And,
supplying tonight's dance floor fillers, will you please
welcome Woohoo! It's the Mary Arches, everyone. APPLAUSE
Now, the Mary Arches are going to put their spin on some
classic party songs. You lot shout out when you think you
know what they're playing. OK, is that makes sense? Yes!
Right, so, Mary Arches, are you ready? Yeah! All right, take
it away. Shout out to the bear. OK, one, two, three. WHISTLE
BLOWS Whitney Houston, all the way! CHEERING That's the
best thing you've got at night, everyone. Let's see. MUSIC
PLAYS CHEERING APPLAUSE OK, are you ready for your next one?
Yeah. Take it away. MUSIC PLAYS WHISTLE BLOWS WHISTLE BLOWS
Any out there? Anyone? Is it upside your head? LAUGHTER I
really wish it was, but no, it's not. All right, let's find
out. Off you go, then. MUSIC PLAYS APPLAUSE That was very
powerful. OK, this is the last one. Oh, my God. So, listen
really carefully. What do you think this is? MUSIC PLAYS Oh,
my God! Yes! That's correct. It was, come on, I need. Come on,
I need. Come on, I need. I love you, me. Everything. MUSIC
PLAYS OK, come on, I need by Texas Midnight Riders. And thank
you very much. Give it up for the Mary Archies, then.
CHEERING APPLAUSE Now, Christy, I believe that you can
complete a Rubik's Cube in under four minutes. I can. But
sadly, we haven't got the time for that. LAUGHTER But stay
with us, cos Tom is on his way with a special gift for you. See
you in a bit, guys. CHEERING AND APPLAUSE Welcome back.
We're all here. Scarlett, Nabil, Ashling and Christy. OK,
who fancies a game of Artie Party? APPLAUSE So, Scarlett,
right, you've got a card with some party words and phrases on
it, and all you need to do is draw them, and the rest of the
panel and Christy will... Guess what they are. You can't use
any letters or symbols, OK? But I can draw the item. Yeah. All
right, Scarlett, your time starts now. A balloon. Yeah!
Well done. So that's number one. Well done for wiping your
own board. Beautiful artist, Scarlett, I have to say. I
really saw that balloon. I've got an A star at Textiles. Get
on with it. Um... Number two, yeah. Not A number two, but... A
hole. Down a hole. Stone skimming. Are you doing the same one
as I've done? Yeah! Is that a T-cup, am I...? Er... Falling
out of a hole. Frisbees. Falling out of... Tumbling out of a
hole. Air hole. Definitely hole, I cut. All right,
Scarlett, what is it? The sausage roll. LAUGHTER It's a
sausage roll. Why did you nod at me every time I said a hole?
Cos it grabs the roll. I genuinely thought you were doing the
wrong one. And your next one. Moose Christmas reindeer.
Roondi. Opposite of him. Moose hunter. Spectacled. Yeah!
APPLAUSE And your final one, number ten. One second. The
Tate Britain. Scarlett Moffat exhibition. I'm not a part of
the big... Yes, Will Taken! Yay! This right, erm... Vape.
Vaping. Er... Er... Er... Foghorn. Party poppers. Yay!
APPLAUSE Scarlett, you've done a party popper. I think
you've got it slightly wrong. Look at the card again. Party
pooper. Lots of party poppers you've had! I'm glad you
didn't have to draw that. Hi! Yes, that's absolutely well
done. APPLAUSE OK, Christy, we're going to ask the panel now
to tell us what they loved about watching you on Bake Off
Scarlett. Everything. And I really hope that you take some
self-confidence from this because watching you, like, I
just feel like sometimes you're so hard on yourself, but you
made it to the quarterfinals, like, you're amazing, so I
hope that you take that with you. And yeah, you're just
wonderful. Aw, thank you. Yeah, yeah. APPLAUSE Vaping. As
someone who is naturally very anxious, like, I always doubt
myself. I enjoyed watching someone like me overcome that.
You were fantastic, and I'm sure you make a lot of people
happy that you don't even know about. APPLAUSE That's
great. Not for me, sorry. LAUGHTER You know what I loved? I
loved that you openly said, like, you hadn't done anything
for yourself. And I think so many people who you do get
motherhood and be a joy and stuff, but that it's not your only
purpose and that to do something for yourself is so
important. And to come out of those years going, actually, I
have a little ambition for myself and it becomes a big one and
here you are. So I think that's usually important. Thank
you. APPLAUSE I'm excited. OK, thanks very much, everyone.
And now here comes Tom and his trolley. APPLAUSE Oh, my,
Gryffie. Will you tell us what you're going to take away from
your time on Bake Off? Just to believe in myself more and just
all my lovely baking family. Oh, well, that's another thing
to say. And here's what I think. LAUGHTER Christy, you are
one hell of a baker. I understand your need for perfection,
of course. I'm just the same. Look at my hair. Christy, you
make candy canes out of cheese straws in a tent. And not many
people can say that, perhaps for obvious reasons. You were
brilliant on this year's Bake Off and you should be so proud
of yourself. Just don't you forget it. We're all very, very
proud of you here. So remember that. Thank you. APPLAUSE
Thanks, Tom. And now, Christy, let's all enjoy a look back at
your time in the tent. I'm trying to just take a look and enjoy
it. I think it looks really appetising. Christy, you need my
bestie, though. Wow. They look impressive inside. I'll
tell you that now. You have. Beautifully moist inside and
crispy. So what I will do... Thank you. Just my instinct,
yeah. The winner is this one, Christy. Perfect. Oh, my gosh.
I think you need to do it again. Shanaf. You're lovely. Oh,
that's gorgeous, yeah. It looks wonderful. It's perfect,
isn't it? They're beautiful. I've never had French Pan with
Basby in it before. That's amazing. I love that. This week's
star baker is Christy. It's been like a life journey. You
know, I've done really well. I love that. Tastes great. Star
baker, handshake. Can these things mean the world to me? Go,
go! I'm so proud of myself. APPLAUSE So, Tom, if you could
reveal all... APPLAUSE So, Christy, they are with your
willing lemon and thyme drizzle cake, beautiful chocolate
box, and Mr Holly was favourite picnic pies. Christy,
everybody. CHEERING So, that's it for this week. A big thank
you to Tom, to Christy, to the Mary Archies, all our studio
bakers, and to our celebrity panel, Scarlett Moffat, Nabil
Abdul Rashid, and Ashling B, see you same time next week for
the Bake Off Semi-Final. Goodbye. Are you a star baker in the
making? If you'd like to apply for the next series of Bake
Off, visit Channel4.com or would slash take part.
Qualifications in the bag, but England still need a point to
make sure of topping the group. Full coverage as Malta come
to Wembley live from 7 o'clock tomorrow, which means that
GoverBox will be on a bit later than usual at 10 o'clock.
We're next tonight, Taskmasters keeping up with the times,
with Alex's very own VAR system. Although the fact he's
called it the Dream Crusher doesn't bode well, I reckon.
APPLAUSE MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC MUSIC