[Silence]
Previously on Great Chocolate Showdown. Let's get down to
it. Nine Home Bakers raced their chocolate bar game. The
pressure is on. Tim's berry nougat chocolate bear was the
judge's favorite, bar none. Your teddy is gorgeous.
Granting him the coveted golden whisk. In the elimination
challenge, the bakers tried to shred the competition with a
cheese and chocolate dessert. Some cheese, some
chocolate, some anxiety. Allie's dark chocolate manchego
Paris Breast earned her the win. Nice work. Leaving Donna
and Ashley in jeopardy. I did not do my... Donna's chocolate
and breed tartlet sent her home. Now only eight bakers
remain on the road to sweet success. Come on guys, let's keep
going. You got it. The last elimination challenge, I was in
the top two and it felt great. I am learning so much in this
competition. So far I'm 0 for 2 in technique tests. I plan on
really focusing on what they have to teach us. I'm ready to
win this. Hello bakers. Now you've all shown us some
impressive chocolate baking. But to learn more skills that
will sweeten your dessert game. And if you pay attention,
this next technique test will be as easy as pie. Oh. Pie.
Bakers. Today I'm going to show you how to make one of the most
beloved desserts. The pie. I'm nervous because I have
never, ever made a pie before. I have my chilled pieces of
dough. It's time to roll in line our pie shell. Start in
small, don't try and push the dough in one direction, one
way. Because it will spring back and you'll find it changes
its shape once it fakes. So little motions, rotate. If
you're nervous about lifting up your pie dough, you can roll
it over the pin if you wish. Bring the plate to the dough and
then unroll it in place. Now we want to create a polished edge
to our pie pastry. I'm securing the pastry onto my pie plate
so then it won't go anywhere. Your oven should be preheated
to 375 Fahrenheit and you bake it for 20 minutes. Here is our
baked pie shell out of the oven. So this filling has been
pre-cooked and chilled down. So it's ready to go into my pie
shell. Now this pie, we know it's going to be delicious, but
it's lacking a little something. We need you to captivate us
with a beautiful decorated top. I'm going to show you how to
create a couple of simple pastry rosettes. You take four
discs of pastry and you want to overlap them. You start from
once when you cut it in half, open up your petals and you've
got lovely little rosettes. Chef Anna's pie decorations
are amazing. She has such an attention for detail. Her
creativeness is out of this world. Bakers, it does seem to me
there's something missing. Chocolate! Thank you! We have
to see you temper some chocolate for the top decor of your
pie. We want a piece of pie art. We ate chocolatey pie with a
colorful, creative top. Become Picasso's of pastry as you
serve us some delicious slices of pie art. You'll be judged
on originality, presentation, taste, and in this test,
your pie technique. The three bakers who present us with the
most impressive pies will be granted sweet safety. Oh! And
will not have to bake in the chocolate elimination
challenge. Yes! And Tim, remember there are only four
challenges left. You use your golden whisk. Bakers, the
pantry is fully stocked with the finest chocolate and
ingredients. You'll have two and a half hours to complete
your pies. Ready? Steady? Get your sweet on! We have not much
chocolate at the top. Take what I need, take what I need. This
technique test is just so much fun. In the pie art, it's
creative, it's expressive, but before the bakers do
anything else, they need to get their pie and resting.
Chilling in the fridge to get in the pie delt, time to relax.
While that's happening, they can make their filling or
other components. I'm absolutely comfortable with making
pies. Going into this technique test, my strategy is to get
my pie crust and refrigerate as quick as possible. I'm
making a dark chocolate raspberry cream pie with maple
walnuts in. Oh, maple walnuts? Yes. That sounds good.
Walnuts and chocolate go very well together. I'm putting
things that I like. I am making a chocolate raspberry basil
pie. Basil is one of my favorite herbs and I love
raspberries, so why not combine them two? I just grabbed a
grapefruit thinking it was an orange. But you know, there's
always a couple of hiccups when you're baking. I am making a
Mississippi mud pie. One, because I'm from Mississippi.
And second, because it has a lot of chocolate in the pie.
Normally, I'm a cookess and cake girl. I just have to watch
the clock and make sure I get everything done in time. What
are you making? Chocolate pastry cream. Oh my God, it sounds
like a dream. This smells really, really good. I'm really so
focused. Bakers, two hours left. That's why I have one
nephew and five nieces, all of whom are basically little
monkeys. So I want this pie to be inviting, fun, and full of
color. I'm making a chocolate peanut butter banana monkey
pie. It'd be really nice for a change for the judges to
actually evaluate one of my technique tests. I move on to my
pastry cream. Once this pastry cream is done, it's going to
have to sit in the fridge so it can firm up. So I'm just making
sure all the chocolate is melted. Get in my pie, duh. So for
this technique test, I am making a dark chocolate bourbon
pie. Come on, summer. Summer! I'm choosing dark chocolate
because it's going to play really well with the bourbon. A
few more minutes on my pie crust. We should be ready to work.
For perfect pie dough, you don't need to chill it for too
long. Start rolling. I'm just trying to shape my pie dough
into my pie pan. I see a lot of baking pots on the stove. They
have to be constantly multitasking. Does anybody have the
Dutch cocoa? I do. Yes, friend, down the street. There you
go. Thank you. I know brownies don't necessarily go with
pies, but I'm making the pie that I want to eat, and I'm going
to put that brownie in the crust. I've made my sauce. I'm
making my milk chocolate mousse now, and I'm going to get
started decorating and working on my pie. I smell a burning
crust. Is it yours? Yeah, everyone check your oven.
Something's definitely burning. Is it mine? I don't think
so. Is it yours? No, I just took mine out and popped it back in.
Me too. That's my stuff burning. My walnuts are burnt. Mike!
My walnuts are burnt. These walnuts are the key to my
dessert. I forgot they were in the oven. I'll make another
batch. These walnuts give the pie some crunch, and it gives
it a little bit of sweet for the better chocolate. I'm pretty
excited about this challenge with the pie. Once their pie
shells are in the oven, then our bakers can fill the oven. I'm
going to focus on decor. This technique test is as much about
time management as it is pastry execution. In college I
played football, and our mascot was the dragons. So I'm
choosing to make a dragon for my pie art. I'm very artistic
and I love to draw, and one of my favorite things growing up
was watching mermaid movies. So I'm making a Mississippi
mermaid mud pie. We got some mermaid tails going on. Bakers,
you have one hour left. One hour left. Hello! Our bakers have
a lot of little decisions to make in terms of how they're
going to compose their pie art on top. I did individual
pieces. You could easily use a circle of pastry, add things
to it, and then bake the whole thing. This is a snow globe.
When I was younger, I used to collect snow globes. I wanted to
be really Christmassy. When the judges look at my pie, I
would really like them to envision snow globes and the magic
of winter. There will be a Christmas tree and some foley and
the shape of a snow globe. I still have all this stuff I have to
paint. Doesn't look orange. Time is running out and I need to
get my pie decorations as well as my tempered chocolate onto
the pie. Anybody have any leaf cutouts? I do. You want some? I
do. Here you go. I didn't use that one. I love you all. So my
inspiration for this pie is my evening walks that I take
every night. I look at the leaves and the beautiful flowers
growing and I am going to put that on top of my pie. Okay, she's
not too bad. It's time to start putting my chocolate pieces
onto my pie. I've never done it. In the prairies, we have the
most beautiful sunsets and the most beautiful lakes you
could ever possibly imagine. I am hoping that the judges see
a bit of home. So I also cut out an orange t-shirt. I wear the
orange pin on my apron every day to honor my people, our
history. So my pie is dedicated to all of the residential
school survivors out there to hopefully bring awareness to
it. It's almost time for pie. 15 minutes left, Bakers. Come
on, guys. Let's keep going. Every time you're trying to
finish line, that's when things really go wrong for me. I'm
not munking around. Oh, wow. This looks horrible. This is
not looking like a dragon's face. It's looking more like a
wounded animal. We're going out of time. Five minutes left,
Bakers. Let's go. Come on, I'll make it. And it's a success.
There's five minutes left to this pie challenge and I'm
arranging my footprints, my leaves and my flowers all the
way around, hoping that the judges will see that it's me
taking a walk through nature. Time is going to be a crunch,
but I got this. Come on, come on, come on. I don't want to jinx
myself, but I feel like things are going really well. Ten,
nine, eight, seven, six, five, four, three, two, one.
Time's up. Pie pie. Good job. Good job, Ellie. This pie
tastes like home and it looks like home. I'm doing a walk
through nature on my first pie ever. This has got to impress
the judges. You did it. But now we have to come around and take
a closer look because we will only be tasting five of your
desserts. Tim, the question on everyone's mind, would you
like to use your golden whisk? At this point, it's very
tempting to use this golden whisk. I can move ahead without
any issues. I have thought about it long and hard and I'm
going to keep fighting. I'm going to hold on to the whisk. In
that case, there are still three spots for me to safety. So
there's only five of us that are going to be tasted this time
around. That means my chances are even slimmer than the last
two technique tests. Bakers, we asked you to create an
eye-catching pie. Now taste your desserts. Mike, you're up
first. Please bring us your pie. I have five nieces and one
nephew, so I thought I would celebrate my little monkeys. So
I present to you a chocolate, peanut butter, banana, monkey
pie. I was initially drawn to the bananas. You hit the color
quite well. Your pie crust looks a touch uneven. It was
probably rolled a little too much in one direction. OK.
Shall we give it a taste? Yes, please. Mike, you nailed the
chocolate. Your pastry cream was bitter, but because of the
sweetness of the banana and the peanut butter butter cream,
it all balanced beautifully. Your chocolate looks
tempered. That's just bananas. Nice work, Mike. Thank you.
I have successfully tempered chocolate for the first time.
I could not be happier right now. Please bring us your pie. I
made a white chocolate, Saskatoon Berry Sun Pie. My pie art
is home in Green Lakes, Saskatchewan. In Canada, I also
added an orange t-shirt for all residential school
survivors. And that's why you wear the orange pin. Wear it
every day. To have that connect to you so personally, I think
is beautiful. That is a striking pie. Thank you so much for
sharing it with us. You created such a beautiful, large
swatter. That braid came together beautifully. That's a
fantastic use of the pie pastry. Thank you. Allie, I love
your chocolate work. Thank you. The detail, nice clean
lines. Your chocolate is beautifully tempered. You hear
it. In your pie pastry, you achieved flakiness. It is cooked
all the way through. Allie, thank you so much. Well done.
Thanks. And now we'd like to try Charlie's Pie creation. I
made a chocolate raspberry basil outdoor pie. So every day I
take a walk past yards with beautiful flowers, leaves on
trees. You have my little feet. That's the path that I'm
taking on the pie. We were drawn to your pie because of the
color and the texture well delivered. I don't think your
footsteps were clear, whether they were fish. The
detailing was hard to read. Your flowers and leaves are an
example of when pastry dough has either been over rolled or
not allowed enough time to rest. When it baked, it
contracted. Okay. Thank you. Charlie, the flavor was there
for me. The use of the almonds, of course, you need something
that strong, that powerful to match with the raspberry. The
brownie was so moist against the raspberry flavors. Great
combination. Thank you. The next dessert we'd like to try
belongs to... Meredith. Please bring us your pie. When I was
younger, I used to collect snow globes. So I made a
peppermint mocha snow globe pie. And I really wanted it to be
like a winter wonderland. Your small snowflakes have very
fine detail. So that tells me you worked your pie at the same
time. The pie pastry on top is under baked. And the rest we
shall see when we slice into it. Meredith, when I taste your
dessert, it's unbelievable. Your pastry cream, it's sharp
in chocolate. You're going to ask the mocha flavor in there
really takes on that chocolate flavor. It's like drinking
an actual mocha. That's what I was going for. Now you need to
work on the details on the outside. You just got to push
yourself. You're looking chocolate decor, tempered
chocolate. Thank you so much. Thank you. Only one pie left to
taste. And that pie belongs to... Only one pie left to taste.
And that pie belongs to Emma. The theme of my pie is the season
of fall. I made a chocolate caramel pecan fall pie. I love the
color work and the delicacy of your leaves, but we are seeing
a lot of the plain filling. Many pies have a full second
crust, so it just would have added volume to see double the
amount of leaves to make a statement. Emma, the flavor was
awesome. The caramel pecan crunch allowed the dark
chocolate ganache and the milk chocolate to shine. That
salt drew out the flavor. But the decor, even though you did
give us chocolate, that to me is like an afterthought.
Bakers, we asked you to tap into your creative side and make
us a piece of pie art. Some of you presented pies that were as
pretty as pictures, but a few of you need to be less hasty with
your pastry. Emma and Mike, please step forward. The three
of you had our favorite desserts of this challenge well
done. But there was one baker that presented a pie that was
both striking and scrumptious. And that dessert belongs to
Ali. This is two best dishes in a row for me, and I am on cloud
nine. Mr. The three of you, please go take a seat in sweet
safety. Don't mind if I do. That means the rest of you must
bake in the upcoming chocolate elimination challenge that
will send one of you home. Bakers, by now you know we love big
flavor. And striking the right balance of flavor is more
than just a matter of taste. Why is there a big tongue in the
middle of the kitchen? We're sliding in to taste
sensations. For your next chocolate elimination
challenge, we want you to create a plated chocolate dessert
that showcases one of the basic flavor sensations. Salty,
sour, bitter, savory, and since all desserts are sweet,
we've replaced sweet with spicy. To find out which taste
sensation will be your inspiration, ride on our flavor
slide. Meredith, you're up first. Ooh! Oh! Sour! Tim. Look
out, Malin! Spicy. Ashley. Bitter. Kristen. Savory.
Charlie. So not sliding. Salty. Bakers, understanding how
to combine and balance flavors in baking is essential.
Deliver us a plated dessert that celebrates sensation and,
of course, chocolate. The pantry is fully stocked with the
finest ingredients. You have two hours to complete your
desserts. The baker who presents us with our least favorite
dessert will be going home. Ready? Steady? Get your
chocolate on. All right, Charles, come on. Get some of
these. Get some of these. The taste sensation that I'm going
to be showcasing is sour. Glug. When I hear sour, the first
thing I think about is sour cherries from my mom's cherry
tree. I'm soaking these sour cherries in raspberry
liqueur. For this chocolate elimination challenge, I am
making a chocolate buttermilk cake with sour cherry
filling and the balsamic caramel. Ooh! Meredith! That is so
good! It's so strong! I love that our chocolate elimination
challenge is about flavor sensations. Chocolate is such a
unique flavor. You can pair almost anything with it. We want
our bakers to find the balance between the chocolate flavor
and that flavor sensation. So I got spicy. I love spicy. And
when I did spicy the first time, I won Sweet Safety. I'm
making a spicy dark chocolate lava cake with candy ginger
chocolate bark. So I'm going to add some chili powder to the
lava cake, and I'm going to finish it off with a little bit of
cayenne pepper. Got to bring the heat, baby. I want to get the
sweetness, and then at the end, I want to feel the heat. I
don't want that heat right in the beginning because it will
ruin my palate. Hopefully I can hold on to this gold. My whole
strategy is built on taking risk. I like to experiment with
really big flavors, and if not, don't do well. I have the
golden whisk. I can move forward in the competition without
a hesitation. Oh, I like that. Oh, my gosh, I have bitter.
What am I going to do with this? What are you making? I'm right
now about to make my coffee chocolate mousse. Oh, that
sounds good. For this elimination challenge, I'm making a
chocolate coffee mousse tart with grapefruit ganache. A
couple of minutes before for that dough. The coffee extract
is very strong. In order to make it taste good, you have to add
sweet. So that's where the chocolate comes in. One hour and
30 minutes left, Bakers. Come on in, Bakers! What
ingredients are you using, Kristen? Miso and soy sauce. Oh,
miso and soy sauce? Yep. I used to work at an Asian bistro, so
I'm familiar with the flavors. My plan is to send miso
brownie with a soy sauce caramel. So it's a sweet and savory
combination. Kristen has got soy sauce and miso paste. That
could be interesting, but that could also... Because
there's a lot of salt in both of those. I know how to cook
savory main courses, but as savory dessert, I'm not so sure
about them. Just got to stay focused and do what I can.
Kristen doing things over here. Don't hype me up too much. So
coming in to this elimination challenge, I'm pretty good
with salt. Now, there are some salts in the pantry that I've
never seen or heard of. Blur de sel, which is a fancy French
sea salt. And I've never used pretzel salt before. I always
found when cooking with chocolate and salt, we're using the
salt as the flavor of the chocolate. It's fun picking all
these salts, but it's also scary because I do not want to give
too salty. I am making a chocolate cake with a mango ganache
and a pretzel salt nut crumble. Let's go, Charlie! Thank
you. Right now, I'm working on my tart, though, about to roll
it out and put it in the oven. My goal is to get this tart golden
brown, nice and soft, and done. To the oven. So next, for the
grapefruit ganache, I shaved some grapefruit in there. And
the grapefruit has a powerful, bitter flavor. There we go.
That was just some mango puree. So I'm making a mango
ganache, and it's going to go on top of my chocolate cake.
This ganache has the right amount of salt to bring out that
natural sweetness in your chocolate. Just cleaning up a
little so I can focus. As I'm making my caramel, I think it's
pretty thin, so I heated up some more. Next, I take my cakes
out of the oven. They are not elegant or pretty. I'm not going
to plate these cakes, so... All right. I don't like doing
those things. These cakes won't come out of the mold. I am
literally freaking out. I'm not having good luck with hands
today. There is a lot of pressure today. I'm not ready to go
home. I'm not having good luck with hands today. I can't use
these cakes because they are not elegant or pretty. Okay. I
give up on making this cake, so I'm just going to make a flat
one. In this elimination challenge, we have to make a
showcase a key taste sensation. I have more batter, so
instead of the cake pans, I'm just going to plate safe and put
them on a sheet pan. And it should make my cakes look better. I
wonder if it was the batter itself or her treatment of the
pan. I don't know that there's enough time for this. At the
end of this elimination challenge, one of these bakers will
be going home. So this is my pistachio hazelnut with a little
pretzel sauce. For this salt and nut crumble, I am using a
hefty teaspoon of pretzel salt. I give the nut crumble a
taste, and I'm a little bit salty. If you're used to much
salt, there's no going back. I'm just preying my dessert.
It's not overly salty. And then I think I should add some
whipped cream. The judges are getting too much salt. They
can take a small, different whipped cream to break up some of
that salty flavor. Chocolate spread out. So now I'm going to
show off my chocolate skills. I'm going to make a
three-layer chocolate bark with almonds and candy ginger.
The good thing about candy ginger, it kind of gives you a
sweet but spicy flavor. Next, I want to make a chocolate
garnish. So what I'm going for is an abstract lava feel. I am
no artist. To me, it kind of looks like a flower. Come behind
you. Come behind you, too. Now, I'll start on my walnuts. I
have a lot going on right now, but I know I have to make time to
get the judges an extra crunch with my dessert, so I start to
make caramelized walnuts. Hopefully my chocolate is in
temperate today. I haven't had my old snap moment from Chef
Steve, and I really want that. Just going to keep thinking
positive. The caramel tastes great. I still taste the
balsamic. My cake is made. I'm about to temper chocolate.
Now the curls to make it look like black horse cake. She cute,
Meredith. She cute. Temper friend. To make this tempered
chocolate into a garnish, I just sprinkle the flow of the
cell over the chocolate. It's a salty salt, but it's like a
good salty. It's fun picking all these salts, but it's also
scary because they all have to work together. 20 minutes,
you guys. Sometimes I make the wildest dessert, but I want to
give the judges what they want, and that's a more refined
plate. Just in case the miso is now outstanding, I want to add
the glaze for just the extra touch. Goo it. This dessert is
going to be amazing. On top of my brownie, I'm going to put my
miso glaze caramelized walnuts. I'm a little nervous. I
need to break this up. My idea for this dessert is to place my
lava cake front and center. Next, I'm going to sit the mousse
right next to it, and I'm going to divide it by the chocolate
bar. I think I did overtook my caramel a little bit. I don't
want to give up on this caramel because it has my sour and
balsamic vinegar. It's time to start assembling my plate.
Buttfakers! This plated dessert, I'm putting different
colors. I'm putting different flavors. I'm making my tart
have height. I'm making this plate stand out. I've got to get
moving, ready to plate. I want it to look like a piece of art
hanging in a museum. Good job, everybody. Keep going. Keep
going. Keep going. I need some color up here. Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six, five, four, three, two, one. Big A! Woo!
We have finished our bake, and I just completed my plated
dessert. And it looks amazing. I'm so excited. I really made
something that I've never made before, and it looks good.
I'm happy about it. Well done, bakers. Tim, will you be using
your golden whisk? Should I use the golden whisk? If I do use
it, I'll get the bake again. If I don't, there's a chance I
could go home. I think I'm going to take a whisk and save my
golden whisk. I strongly believe that I don't have the worst
dessert here. Okay, bakers, now it's time to taste your
desserts. Bakers, we asked you to create a chocolate
dessert that highlights a selected taste sensation.
Charlie, please bring us your dessert. I chose salty, and
this is a chocolate cake with a mango ganache and a
pretzelsauce nut crumble. A refined plating, but I think
you would have had time to put your whipped cream in a piping
bag, give it a pipe that would match the overall look of the
dessert. Thank you. Charlie, I've got to be honest, I didn't
like your dessert. I loved your dessert. You managed to
highlight not just salt but mango and chocolate all at once.
Thank you. I did. Salt came through in your pretzel nut mix.
So did you temper the chocolate? Oh snap, Charlie, you did.
Charlie tempered the chocolate. I think this may be the best
critique I received on a dessert. Charlie, thank you so
much. Thank you. Meredith, please bring us your dessert. I
picked sour. I made a chocolate buttermilk cake with a sour
cherry filling and a balsamic caramel. Chocolate cake? Do
you know what this reminds me of? Black Forest cake. I would
have called it that. To have a little more open space around
your dessert allows us to focus on what you want us to see.
Meredith, it's a simple cake. I got that intense hit of
chocolate, but I missed out on the sour. I had one sour
cherry, but it's not enough. Meredith, thank you so much.
Thank you. After having problems with my caramel, my cake
wasn't sour enough. Ashley. I got bitter. Today I made you a
chocolate coffee mousse tart with a grapefruit ganache.
You've got two different styles of piping on one side.
You've got dots on the other. Something should be pulled
away. It's a bit distracting. I saw your frustration when
you pulled your tart shell out of the oven and it had sunk.
Sweet dough, you don't have to line bake, but a pastry like
this without sugar or egg in it, you must. Your chocolate
coffee mousse had a punch of coffee. You got the bitter and it
had the chocolate. The bitter grapefruit and chocolate
ganache, I got the bitter in it, but there wasn't enough of
it. Did you try each component of your dessert? I did. And did
you try a biteful together? I didn't try a biteful together.
Next up, we'll be trying everything together. The bitter
was there. I was just craving a little more of it. Thank you so
much. I'm a little nervous about my tart. Kristen. I agree.
So I made a miso brownie with a soy sauce caramel. And my
garnish is milk chocolate. I have to say, the plating is
lovely. You have texture with your different colors and
pipings. Thank you. Kristen, you bring a lot to every
dessert, except now, your tight minute. Restraint was the
key element here. You knew. Soy sauce. Yeah, that fermented
flavor. And it's the soy caramel on the place. I did get a few
crumbs. Crumbs and brownies don't go together. Black cocoa
can dry things out a little bit because of the reduced fat
content. But that's all I got. Thank you. Kristen, what do
you think? Maybe it's too thin, so you know, snap. Yeah. Oh,
no. Oh, snap! Oh, snap! Wait a minute. Amazing job. Thank
you. Tim. I picked spicy. I present to you a spicy dark
chocolate lava cake with candy ginger chocolate bark. Is
there a reason you opted for a flower as a garnish? That's not
really supposed to be a flower. It's kind of like lava coming
out of a volcano. It looked better in my head. Because you
have a rather dramatic garnish, I think a bigger plate would
let the lava cake be the star. What is our heat tolerance
supposed to be here? You know, it may blow you outside, so I
don't know. All right. Tim, I liked your dessert. The
intensity of your chocolate flavor really hits you. And the
heat also hits you. Well done. Thank you. My favorite spice
element on your plate was the candy ginger. That complex
heat with the dark chocolate was sophisticated. I love the
ginger. All right, Tim, when you have tempered chocolate
garnishes and you have a warm dessert, any form of heat will
take it out of temper. Tim, thank you so much. Thank you. I'm a
little worried about my new whisk. Instead of taking a
whisk, I should have went on and used the whisk. TEn Bakers,
we asked you to create a chocolate dessert celebrating a
flavor sensation. Tim, please step forward. You are safe.
Please go join your fellow bakers. This is sweet golden
whisk. Charlie, Kristen, please step forward. The two of
you have the best desserts of this challenge. But there was
one dessert that struck a harmonious balance between
chocolate and bold taste. Kristen. You bet a gal here. And a
little lad. Are you kidding me? Proud of myself. Your miso
brownie was a savory starlet. Please go join your fellow
bakers. Ashley and Meredith, unfortunately, your
desserts were not as successful. Ashley, you took us to
Flavortown with that coffee mousse. However, that
beautiful balance was missing completely in other
components of your dessert. Meredith, you gave us a cake
that was utterly delicious. But what got lost even we asked
for? Unfortunately, one of you must leave this kitchen. The
baker who is going home is Meredith. Meredith. Isn't it
good? That means, Ashley, you are safe. Meredith, saying
goodbye to such a passionate baker is never easy,
especially when they're as tall. Your family will be so
proud of what you've accomplished in this kitchen. I've had
so much fun. And I'm going to miss you guys. Well, don't leave
her standing there. Come on over. I'm going to miss you. You
guys are so cool. I'm so proud of all of you. Proud of you. Love
you, Meredith. I'm proud of everything I did here. And I'm so
happy to have met everyone. And I'm really going to miss
them. I can't wait to show my family everything I've
learned. Next time on Great Chocolate Showdown. It's very
sticky, and I really don't like it. Fruit is on the menu. A
delicious patte de frie. This is a lot. This is so shiny. If
the elimination challenge, the competition gets juicy. My
heart is beating like a thousand miles a minute. And the
homemakers feel the squeeze. Very ugly. I'm really worried
for her. Too big. Not good.