[Silence]
MUSIC In the beginning... Oh, thank you, anyone. ..there
were 12. So, Nicky, tell us about your beaver. LAUGHTER
Now... This is it, the storm is coming. There are three.
Let's see how we go. Why is it doing that? There can only be one
winner. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. Patience.
Oh, no, it didn't dust him in icing sugar, did it? It's not
your best shot. WHISTLING I don't see Tant now, is it? Just
three challenges stand between the finalists and the
Bake-off title. Best of luck. Go, go, go, Josh. Josh's
passion for precision was obvious from week one. I love the
way one of her eyes is completely gone with a frid. By week
two, he had already had the Hollywood handshake. Amazing.
But every week, he's delivered stunning showstoppers.
It's beautiful. Delivering him star baker, not once, but
twice. Just want to be able to have three good last bakes that
I can be happy with, but we shall see. This year's first star
baker, Dan, has often made his life complicated. I am doing
the aromatic flavours of a tiger in curry. What are you
thinking? And it hasn't always been successful. It's a bit
sandy and drunken. But he's fought back from
disappointment. These aren't baked. Winning more
technical challenges than any of his fellow finalists, the
Hollywood handshake... That's beautiful. ..and was star
baker again in dessert week. I'd love to, wouldn't it? But
I'm against the East too. Little Rugrats this weekend. Such
good lads. I am going to have to really raise my game. Matty's
time in the tent did not begin well. I can't give that to
anyone. But he's listened. It looks like he's been run over.
And learned. The look of it is really very good. Polishing
decoration. Your box is beautifully engineered. And
perfecting flavours. The chilli is great in there. But
despite a handshake and winning star baker twice, he's
never won a technical challenge. I would say that on the
underdog, everyone likes the underdog though, right?
Please. LAUGHTER Welcome back to the Tent Bakers for your
last ever signature challenge. The judges would like you to
bake eight exquisite, highly decorative eclairs. You
should choose two different types in terms of decoration
and flavour. Now, remember, guys, this is the final. So the
judges would like you to bake in the nude. LAUGHTER And when
Noel says judges, he means pru. You have two hours and 15
minutes. On your marks. Good set. Bic! I don't believe this
is the last signature I'm going to do. I'm a bit nervous. I
just hope these look all right. There's a lot of personal
pride for each one of us. We all play sport. We're all
competitive. And when I play football, I always have to wear
two pairs of socks. I've got four pairs of underpants on
today because I'm going to need them. They're going to make
two different types of eclairs and they've got to be
perfect. The pastry needs to be really puffed up and crisp as
anything. But you want beautiful air holes in the inside
which you can fill with cream or custard. But the problem is
you can add too many creams and custards to it and make it
soggy. They've all had two star bakers. They've all had a
handshake. So they are absolutely level-picking. And I
have the clue who's going to win. And if they want to win, the
Great British Baker starts now with the eclairs. Hello,
Dan. Hello, Dan. Good morning. How are you? All right. Tell
us all about your eclairs. What are you doing? So I'm doing
strawberries and cream under a summer fruit punch jelly.
And for my second one, I'm doing a salted caramel mascarpone
cream with a praline ganache on top. Sounds very nice. Yeah,
doesn't it sound good? Dan will top his salted caramel and
praline eclairs with crisp tempered chocolate. His
strawberries and creamy eclairs will be decorated with
shantilly cream and cubes of jelly. Tell us about your shoe.
Some of my first pastries are sort of learnt to make, so I've
got my set recipe and never fails. So far. So far, yeah. Josh
is also hoping to fill shoe pastry with a taste of summer. Is
this some of your own fruit from your own garden? Well,
actually, it's not now, because I've used it all up. You used
all your fruit? I'm just letting it out there. I keep
bringing it all in, and it's all gone. What flavours are you
doing? We're going to do coconut mango and raspberry.
Alongside his summery eclaire, Josh plans another filled
with coffee-pasted cream and topped with dark chocolate
and coffee icing. That's to my brother, because he's not a
huge fruit lover at all. So most of the things that I've been
making recently, he's not really like them. What does he
say? Does he get, yeah, it's all right? Yeah, so he'll try a
bit of... Exactly like that. Thanks for the encouragement.
So you need to melt the butter first, then bring it to the
boil, get your flour in, and people in daylight start to have
it. Unless the finest combined butter, milk and flour with
the perfect amount of egg... I'm smidgened. ..their shoe
will be loose, creating flat, soggy eclairs. I've avoided
shoe pastry like the plague up until this week. Matty's
hoping to play it safe with two classics. Black Forest
Gâteau Eclairs topped with a cursed Chantilly cream and
Bonofia Clairs, featuring a walnut and pecan praline. Are
you all right? I'm so happy for you. I'm so happy that you're
here. Do you feel like you could do this? Yeah, and I've not
really given you that thought. Oh, I never replied, so I
never really had that as, like, a thought process. So you
didn't apply for this? No, Lara replied for me. Oh, I love
Lara. He would never have applied for himself. It's just not
in his nature. He's not braggie. I wanted him to be a part of
something like this, to show to him how amazing he is,
because it doesn't matter how much I tell him. He doesn't
believe me. I don't actually understand most of the things
he's made, if I'm absolutely honest. Especially you,
because you're not a dessert person anyway, really. No, so
it's all a bit over my head. So his ability is obviously
increased as it goes along. It was an anniversary cake last
year, didn't it? Did it? Don't make the lemon cake. Oh, yes.
Yeah, yes. Sorry, very nice. We'll go to school, we'll do all
of his after-school club. Perfect. He'll get in, start
baking straight away, baking until we go to bed. And there
were times when he's being running around the kitchen like a
headless chicken that I thought, oops, like, this is all my
fault. I don't know when the penny's gonna drop that he's
good at baking. I definitely think he can win it. Good luck,
Lattice. Good luck, Lattice. I want you to actually think
about you possibly winning it. Yeah, you've got to start
visualising it. Yeah, that's actually what Lauren says.
Start visualising like you winning. But before any of the
finalists can see themselves winning... Come on, don't
play games. ...they'll need to take a long, hard look at
their shoe. This is the part where I said about trusting your
instinct. You need it to fall off in three seconds. Do you
know how many videos I've had to watch? I want to start piping
them out. I'm just looking for a bit of uniformity. You can
see my hands shaking kind as well. It's shoe. I don't mind if
it's over. Without a dusting of icing sugar, an eclair won't
have its classic crisp shell. I'm doing two different types
of shoe. But Josh has decided to go even further. I've gone
for a chocolate crackerline topping. A couple of
millimetres thickness is all you need. Do or die now.
They're gonna go in 40 minutes. Half an hour, 175. 15
minutes, 200. Take it down to 175 for another 15 minutes.
Maybe 20, maybe 25. I want them to be dry. Oh, no, it didn't
dust them in icing sugar, I haven't did that. Too late now,
innit? You put icing sugar on yours, mate? Yes, mate, did
you? I forgot, didn't I? Oh, no way. It wouldn't be me not
forgetting this, would it? Josh, how you doing, mate? Yeah,
I think okay. Is she looking all right? Yeah. Good lad. It's
looking all over the place, mate. I'm dreaming. It's just
like the most surreal week ever, isn't it? And your kids
don't know that you're a real... I've told them. You've told
them yesterday... My kids don't know that I do this. Don't
they? No. No, it's probably the best way, because I tell you
what, you went down like a lead bloom yesterday when I told
them. What do you mean? What, nothing? Gave you nothing. He
just went, you're lying. I'm gonna give you a little fava
talk, like I'm very disappointed in you. Oh, no. I'm not
angry. I'm just disappointed. Disappointed. On the top,
mate! You're gonna see me! This lie is the biggest burden of
my life, especially when I tell my children. Never lie. But
obviously, this is a sight exception. My eldest sort of
wanders into the kitchen. He doesn't really question
anything. He goes, oh, what are you doing today, Dad? I was
like, yeah, I'm just making an electric guitar out of puff
pastry. He's like, cool. But there's like, wanders off of
his iPad. He just thinks I'm absolutely crack as a thing. But
there are some members of Dan's family that have known what
he's been up to. It's been very difficult keeping it quiet
and not telling the world that my son's in a make-off. I'm so
proud of him. What was Dan like as a little lad? He was a
whirlwind. He was cheeky. He was mischievous as well. The
trophies that he's won, playing football, they used to line
his bedroom walls. It never got to his head that he was man of
the match or player of the year. He's very critical of
himself. I want to make sure I put my kids in bed, you know, and
try and live that sort of normal life and help our three and
other family stuff as much as possible. As soon as eight
o'clock strikes, it's in here until I'm done, basically, so
yeah, it's totally covert, door closed. Look like I'm a good
sleeper. Whatever happens, I'll make sure that I leave the
tent as I came in with a big smile on my face because I've
absolutely loved it. Good luck, Dan. You'll absolutely
smash it. Cheers. Thank you. Do you think he can win? Yes. I
think he can. We're not as dark as we normally are. Bakers,
you are halfway through. As their shoe bakes, the finalists
will need every minute to perfect two delicious fillings.
Creme pâte. This is a chocolate one. Then I'll turn my
attention to the banana one. This is for Maldice lad. I love
to salt the caramel ice cream, so I thought I'd pay homage to a
wonderful boy that he is. Whilst Dan and Matty race to create
separate fillings for each of their two eclairs... Decent.
...Josh has perfected a shortcut. Just prepping pastry
creams now. I've been tweaking with the recipes, so I can
have exactly the same base for both of them. One's going to be
a coffee one. This one has got coconut milk. Just means I can
do them a little bit quicker because I know it's a lot of
pressure on today. That's our VIP experience at Gardeners
World. Very clever lad. He likes perfection, so he will keep
going and doing something until he's got as best as he can
get. See, Nanny always has a smile on her face wherever we
are. She's always got colourful necklaces on. I'm pretty
much the same as she is now. He's a love of baking. He did stem
from being with Nanny. My mum always fetched them out of
school. They'd go back to her house and then we would be
baking. Josh's Nan Frida first encouraged him to apply for
Bake-Off back in 2019. Looking very smiley. She died in
2021. Nanny was a big part of him applying the second time
around. He really wanted to do it for her because... She so
wanted him to be on that show. She loved all his baking. She
says, you go for it, you go for it. And he's gone and he's got to
the final. And I can't believe it. Sorry. Oh, mum. I know. Do
you want it, Josh? I mean, it would be lovely, wouldn't it?
Come on, Josh! All I'm visualising in my head is what my show
stuff should look like. What's the one thing you're going to
miss from the tent? You, of course. It's the right answer!
It's the right answer! It's seen a bit, Mum. Apart from not
putting the icing sugar on, so they're not as hot as they're
like, looking alright, I'm quite a pooper. Five minutes. I
think I'm alright with how it looks. Let's give it a minute.
Out of my depth. Halston's just informed me. He literally
went, what are you going to miss most out of this tent? And you
said you to her. It's absolutely furious. I thought we had
something, Chumpt. Seven years I've been doing this, Josh.
Seven years! I'm going to pick some holes in the top of him,
too. That's a little steamy escape. Chocolate cream
patty's done. The chantilly cream is whipped. Trying to
multitask. Bakers, you have half an hour left. Oh, you're
joking me. You having a tin bath? This is it, my stormy's
coming. This is banana for the banoffee. The shoe, up a
minute off being done. Really, really happy. I can just hear
that they're hollow. Just going to poke some holes in them,
into the least thing. Then I'm going to put them back in just
for like five minutes. This just, hopefully, completely
dries them out. I've left a lot of them on the body, straight,
haven't I? No, they're not soft. This tent does strange
things to me. Fortunately, I've got lots of really good
ones, so I can just pick my four favourites. Cherry jam. I'm
just going to blitz this so it can fold through into the
cream. Yeah, that's cool. These are going to be macerated
with some of fruit punch. Let's see how I get on. Yeah, why is
it doing that? This is coffee pastry cream. I'll put a bit in
the first hole, then I'll go for the second hole, and then
I'll stop once this first hole starts to ooze out again. So I
know that I've gone all the way through. You have 15 minutes
left. I don't think I'm going to be able to do it, am I? Creme
pat first. I need to get as much in as I can. Chantilly cream.
Wallah. I see. It's difficult to get the bananas to squeeze
through. This is my debut appearance of a transferring onto
acetate. I'll just do some very thin lines of chocolate.
This is my praline paste. This is going into my ganache. You
have five minutes left. Just about OK, time-wise. You just
want to finish off these other ones now? I'm going to run out
of filling, I think. Oh, f***! Sorry. Bakers, you only have
one minute left. One minute? I just don't want to run around
on a night. F***, babe. Oh, he's slipper. Bakers, your time
is up. Please step away from your final signature
challenge, Eclers. It's judgement time in the final
signature challenge. Hi, Josh. Hello. Hi, Josh. Hi, Ed.
Like the look of them, I think they're all pretty much the
same size, pretty uniform across the board. Well, that's
perfectly filled. I'm always so cross when I have an empty
clear. The flavours are very delicate, but they are
absolutely delicious. I think, for me, it's a little bit too
sweet. OK. It almost needs a sharpness to make that pop even
more. This is the chocolate coffee. Yeah. Now, that's
clever. Chocolate's the right level, it gives a lovely
texture to it as well, the crackling on the top. Coffee level
is absolutely spot on. Filled well, baked well. That's
delicious. I love coffee, Eclers. And it is perfect. Thank
you, Josh. Thank you. Those cherry on the top look
ridiculous. OK. If you're going to put cherry on the top,
make sure it's all the same. Shall we start with the banana
first? I like the flavour of the banana. You're missing the
caramel. I know you tried to get on the outside. But for
banana lovers, this is perfect. Thank you. Now, that's the
first one we've had that is properly firm. I like the taste of
the black roast gatto. You could have done more cherry. OK.
But I think the chocolate is lovely, the booze is good. And
most of all, I like the crisp, firm, Eclare. Thank you, man.
Thank you. These look a bit messy. These, it's the wrong
shape for this. You can't have something that's too big that
sits over the top, shadowing your world of need. I think
you've attempted too much. They do look very soggy. The
flavour is lovely, it's not too sweet, it's really
strawberries and cream, but it's a bit soggy. You've
destroyed it by adding too much cream to the top. This is the
praline, isn't it? Not convinced about the flavour on that.
You're not. I think it's probably the grain. I agree that the
filling is not satin smooth, but I think the flavour's
great. I think it looks a mess. Paul picked up on all my
technical issues, and again, I've been guilty of
overthinking it. Nine weeks ago, I would not have been able
to produce anything like that, so... Yeah. Weird. I think I
have quite a strong signature overall. We're just going to
technical now as we get through, and hopefully it isn't just
step one, make this, and that's it. I'm hoping for a little
bit of help along the way. The baker's last technical
challenge is as ever a total mystery. It's time for your
final technical challenge, and today it's been set for you
by Mr Paul Hollywood. What can we say about Paul Hollywood?
We've heard his poetry, we've seen his dance moves, we've
seen him stripped down to trunks and wrestle a live bear. I'm
sure you've all fallen in love with him, and he loves you too,
although he will destroy you one by one. Paul, have you got
any words of advice for our incredible finalists? For
perfection, you're going to need patience. As ever, this
technical challenge will be judged blind, so we're going to
have to ask these two to leave the tent. And it's the last
technical challenge, so you know where they're going,
don't you? Where they're going? To make sweet, sweet love.
LAUGHTER For your final technical challenge, Paul would
like you to bake a batch of nine lardy cake slices. Now, the
judges will be looking for perfectly laminated dough
packed with soaked fruit and homemade candied peel. You
have three hours... ..on your marks. Get set. Bake! Right,
let's have a look at you. A lardy cake? I've heard the name,
but I don't have a clue what one looks like. No one makes lardy
cake, do they? Not since the war. No, it sounds like one from
that era, doesn't it? Do you not know what a lardy cake is? No.
Oh, dear. What a lovely nostalgic bake for a final. Lardy
cake. We've revisited a British classic. It's been around
for hundreds of years, and it was a way of using up
predominantly pig fat. But don't forget, fat is flavour.
Yeah. So I'm really flavoursome. LAUGHTER It's a cross
between a Danish pastry and a bread. This is all about
getting your timing right. Get the dough done as quickly as
possible to get it in that groove, and then you're layering
it with sugar, lard, butter and fruit. On the second prove,
be patient. The longer, the better. That opens the whole
thing up, but it'll condensate, they don't bake it
properly, and it'll look and taste quite raw. You can see the
layers. It's lovely. And you can see all the fruit in there,
evenly distributed. Lard, sugar and a bit of fruit. Lemon.
Line the roast into the baking paper, then grease with lard
and sprinkle with sugar. I assume this is going to help
colour up the lardy cakes. Obviously, you are the oldest of
the bakers. Oh, my God. So you must know what a lardy cake is.
LAUGHTER Make the bread dough. Make the bread dough. The
grams of lard. So I'm going to breadcrumbs it, then add the
yeast and water. I'll just add a little bit at a time. Add the
water, and then once it comes together, I'm going to put the
lard in. I don't know. I don't know if I should be doing it like
this. Sounds really healthy, lardy cake. That's the
problem with baking, isn't it? LAUGHTER Yeah, I've got to do
plenty of runs once it's finished. There. The kneading. How
many times have we made a variation of bread? Is this even
bloody bread? What is this? I don't know. I'll put it in the
proofing drawer. Probably give it half an hour, but we'll
just see how we're doing. I'm not happy with that. I'm just
going to go with it. Bye-bye, my little cherub. I'm going to
go for about 30 minutes, see how it looks. Patience is the
key. Set five. Make diced candied orange, boiling twice in
fresh water, and then a third time in sugar syrup. Using the
microwave for speed, infuse the dried fruit with the tea.
Smells lovely. Do you want any rum in it? No. Cos I'm from
Jamaica, I soak my fruits in rum. There's none. Any vodka?
No. Nothing, unfortunately. Just water. Just water. Dry
with a tea bag. Finalists, you are halfway through. That's
been in for about 35 minutes. That's been in for 45 minutes.
Laminate the dough with lard, butter, filling, mixture.
Doesn't say what to do with the lard. Can I smear the lard?
Let's get it rocking and rolling. I think I might actually
just make sure I've got this evenly spread. Maybe I... Brush
the lard. Have you had a breakdown? What's happening here?
Look at you just pushing lard. It's a bit straight. I don't
even know you might as well just grease ourselves up in lard.
Just go the whole hog. I'm in, if you are. I never turned
something like that down. Right, lamination. Let's make
some spears for lamination. Perform three single letter
folds. Which is that? What is it? That. I'm going to do it
carefully because I want them to see those layers. It's been
around 90 degrees. Obviously, everything's a bit warm,
unfortunately. But that's one letter fold, so I want the
layers to be even. But it's getting a bit warm. That's two.
Stay with me, bread. I need to give it one more fold. I'm not
liking my look at this. Pleased with that. It just says
Proving Tin. The second proof needs to be as long as
possible. But any attempt to speed it up in the heat of the
Proving Draw could melt the lard, ruining the rise in the
lamination. No, maybe I'll just leave it on the side. I don't
know yet. Put in the draw. I really want to give it half an hour
proof. Half an hour? I don't know how long it's a bake for. If I
can work on bake time. Some bake, 40. Bakers, you have an hour
left. So that means proof only 20 minutes. I'm going in. It's
feeling very, very springy, so that's what you want. So, I'm
going to put that in. I'm going to start with half an hour.
This is looking great! Look at that! The worst thing is...
Dan, you don't know whether that is what it's supposed to
look like, do you? I'm not a clue now, can it? It doesn't
look... Brilliant. Bake, I'm thinking 200. 200 may go to
temperature for bread. 30. Maybe 40, maybe 30. Patience.
It's like painful. We have 15 minutes left. I don't know with
it. It's had half an hour now. I'll just give it another... 35
is what I had in my head. I've just cracked up to 220 just to...
WHISTLE Give it a wiggle. Maybe another five? I want you to
leave it in the tin for 10 minutes before turning out. OK,
start that now. I'm bringing it off. It's dark behind. Looks
like it's been cremated. Brush the lidocate with the
reserve orange syrup. Cool completely upside down, then
cut to nine rectangles. There's no chance of me calling it
completely. How long do we have left? Bakers, you've got
five minutes left. Right. Looks pretty tasty, doesn't it?
It is very hot still. And I'll be lucky to cut in any way, shape
or form. I can smell the orange. Looks a bit dense in places.
We can see the layers, don't we? Baked anyway. Baked. Your
time is up. Please bring your lardy cakes and place them
behind your photos. Well, they're varying degrees of
weirdness, aren't they? Paul and Prue are expecting golden
brown lardy cakes. We've clearly defined layers and evenly
packed with plum sweet fruit. Obviously, they've been
struggling with proving. OK. We start with this one. We have
got nine and they are sort of square. That one feels a little
light, which is good. The lamination you can see behind is
going across. The flavour's there. But what's so lovely
about this is the mixed peel. I think that's really
delicious. LAUGHTER Now, moving on to this King Alfred...
There's only slightly King Alfred. Come on, it's...
Slightly. Well, it's caramelised a lot. It is caramelised a
lot. It's over-baked. So, you see the layers, they're sort
of... Not really even. It's a nice flavour. It's just a
little bit dry. It's too dry. It is too dry. Moving on... This
isn't properly baked, is it? No. It's got lots of fruit in it.
It has got lots of fruit in it. Yeah. It needed more proving as
well, but it is quite dense, this. You see how quite raw that
is? Because that doesn't mean laminated properly. It's a
shame. Paul and Prue will now rank the lardy cakes from worst
to first. OK, in third spot, we have... This one, who's this?
Matty, lamination is really bad. You need more proving and
more baking. Right. No problem. Number two, we have this
one. Dan, stayed in the oven a bit too long, didn't he? Which
means, in first place, we have this one, Josh. It's pretty
decent. It's the right colour, and it's certainly the right
flavour. It's well done. Well done, mate. I wasn't after
that. Really, really pleased. I would say Josh has probably
got his nose in front. I'm being, yeah, me and Matty are
scrapping at the bottom. Oh. For the man now. I'm glad I had a
good signature, because otherwise I'd probably be a bit
deflated. There's just one challenge remaining in this
year's Bake Off. What this time, isn't it? In the zone. Well,
guys, we've made it to the final. I just hope the sunshine
comes out. I'm sure it will. Who do you think is bringing the
sunshine right now? Are they even? I think it is pretty even.
I think Josh has got a slight edge. I think he's slightly
ahead. Weirdly, Matty is sitting in second place, I would
say. If he wins it, he would have played an absolute blinder,
because he's always just underneath the top. Can we talk a
little bit about Dan? I think he's going to struggle against
the other two at the moment, but I think what often happens in
the final bake is the pressure gets to him. Anyone of them
could win. What about Amos? Right, so I've just put £20,000
on Amos to win. It's good odds. I bet. BAKERS, it's your final
ever showstopper challenge. The judges would like you to
create an elegant, tiered celebration cake inspired by
your very first bake. They would like you to take your first
bake and elevate it into something incredible, something
that could win the entire competition. You have four and a
half hours for this. On your marks... Get set... BAKER Come
on, Dan. There's lots of elements to do, so timing is
definitely the thing I'm most worried about. I just know how
I want it to look. I will spend the time to make it, and that
will be my downfall. They have to make a minimum three-tier
cake to celebrate their very first bake. But we're looking
for that to be the inspiration for something completely new
and different and wonderful. We want it highly decorated.
We want tartness, we want sweetness, we want textures. This
is the biggest bake they will ever do. If it was me, I'm a big
fan of the lemon drizzle. That would be my favourite. But
sometimes the bakers tell us that this is going to be a lemon
cake and it doesn't have enough lemon flavour. You have to
deliver what you see, you're going to deliver. My first
footstep into baking was a lemon drizzle cake. The lemon
meringue pie as well, so my three-tier cake today is
celebrating both of those two absolute beauties of the
baking world. Dan's final tilt at the title is a towering
triple-tiered love letter to lemon drizzle. Layered with
lemon curd, limoncello creme mousseline and raspberry
compote, his showstopper will be finished with
torch-to-tallion meringue, shiny white chocolate
colours, and one final citrus flourish. I'm also going to
make some macarons as well to decorate around the outside.
Lemon macarons? Yeah, lemon macarons with lemon curd and
raspberry compote filling. I mean, he's obviously been
doing this hand-waving, he knows that we like lemon. Which
is fine, because it was your first bake. Yeah, I love lemon.
Which is lucky. Oh, OK, well, yeah. Well, I need to do it
right. You know, Rahul made me a lemon drizzle cake for my
50th birthday. Oh, did he? Ten years ago. But one finalist is
going even more traditional than a lemon drizzle. The bake
that it stems from is a Victoria sponge. It's the first one I
remember doing with my nan. Josh will combine his first
bakes with his other passion in the seasonal celebration of
his garden with a spring and summer-inspired rhubarb and
strawberry jam and autumnal apple in his Victoria sponges.
It's quite tricky to put apple in sponge to get the flavour to
come through. Yeah. For decoration, what's the whole thing
and it looks like? So, the three tiers are decorated for
spring, summer and autumn. And then I'm going to do a biscuit
greenhouse on top. With boiled sweet windows. Yeah, with
little panels, yeah, like that. Oh, my goodness, Josh. This
is quite a lot. Sounds like a shy stuff, right? Keep your
cool. Yeah, I'll try. Thank you, Josh. I have gone through a
bit of a stronger batter, so it doesn't lose its shape when it
gets put together. Genoese is a little bit of a risk, I guess,
to go on the bottom tier because it's such a light cake. But I
feel like the pro is outweigh the cons on this one. I've gone
for it because it's quick to make, quick to bake, quick to
cool. I've never stacked a cake until this week. Inspired by
the chocolate treats that got him into baking, Matty's
first ever tiered cake will see chocolate Genoese
sandwiched with French buttercream and crumbled brownie,
and a lemon and rosemary Victoria sandwich with a fresh
summer fruit jam. You know that you're a baker. Do you think
you'll bring baking into the schools? What bake would you
bring to your kids? Probably the brownies. I've already
brought them into them once, but they think Lara made them.
Really? Yeah. So you just lied and said my girlfriends had
brought them? Yeah. Why, though? What is so embarrassing
about people knowing that you're a baker? No, I don't know,
really. You don't have to lie anymore because your bakes
taste amazing. How these final showstopper taste could
prove even more important than the spectacular look. I want
the cake to be strong with lemon, but not too sort of like
that. I want to have the essence of Victoria sandwich, but I
also want to elevate it. So this is my roof, I'll... They're
not my strawberries because I have ran out. They've been
ravaged for all of the past weeks I've done. But past weeks
may not bode well for Matty's chosen flavours. In week one, I
had a stinker with the buttercream. So I've changed the
recipe slightly. I kind of need to learn in my own way. It
takes me a few mistakes to learn. I'm slightly worried about
time already. For three tiers, the finalists will need to
bake at least six sponges. Seven minutes left. Which will
require batch baking. Have a little look at that brownie in a
second and all. And a constant eye on the clock. There you go,
I've stopped it. Actually, if that hit Josh in the eye, he had
to go to hospital and the whole thing was cancelled. One way
to stop him winning it, won't it? What are we on to now? I'll be
back. I can start to make the next batter. I'm going to go in my
second mix now. Four and a half hours, do you think it's
enough time? I think it's amper right? No? See how big I got,
Tom? I'm pretty happy with that. These are going in. Just
now, all on me, getting the bakes done quick enough that I can
have enough time. But damn, we'll need to find the time to
bake more than just sponges. I'm only on step four.
Ridiculous. The idea of a macaron is to get a nice skin on
them, so once I've piped them, I'm going to leave them for a
good hour. Let's get these in. This is the Swiss meringue
buttercream now. So I've got two on the go, plus a bit of cake.
That's got about eight minutes to go. Whilst in the tin,
whilst it's still warm, make some holes in it and then just
shove lemon juice on. Soon was lemon in that damn. Sorry,
Paul. Bakers, you're halfway through! What? I know. Love
these ovens. I think they're done there a bit, like, not
straight, but I'll have to trim that. Just taste of the curd,
that tastes beautiful. Done, Matt, done, Matt, done, Matt,
done, Matt. You've just got a big list you're working for.
Yeah, look, the buttercream's are made, jam's made. Not too
bad. Yeah, but this part is where it gets hard. Crazy. Is that
assembly? Yeah. If constructing a three-tiered cake
wasn't hard enough... It's the assembly and making it look
pretty as we're on pants. Whilst building, Dan still has
baking to do. Well behind. It's all right, I'll do it. But
he's not alone. What's going down here? This is my, uh, green
hour on top. You're like, Da Vinci, have you got enough time
to do everything you want to do? I'm never going to have
enough time to do everything that I would love to do, but...
If you've factored that in, of course you have. Yeah, I've
got a couple of backups of what I can do in terms of... That's
why I love you. Just in case things don't go to plan. Plan B and
a plan C in your back pocket. Matty could be in need of his own
plan B. That was a little bit not too dumb. The sponges for his
middle tier are underbaked. That's a bummer. How long do we
have? Bakers, you have one hour left. F***! Can I go home now,
please? Five minutes at really high. And then I'll put them
straight in the freezer. Probably will affect the bake
slightly. But it is what it is. I've got to be prancing this
whole, aren't I? I'm pinging out. I don't think I'm going to
do it. I don't think I'm going to do it. Once you've got these
out, the other one will start straight away doing the
assembly. So we've got chocolate genoese, Swiss meringue
and then chocolate French buttercream and then brownie.
Let's have a little gander. Take them to a dump. I don't know,
but I haven't got that much time left. What stupid idea was
this? That's the last plot of canals. It is, I feel like. I can
go off now. I'm inserting dowels. Or I need to put the dowels
in, actually, as well. This is the white chocolate
buttercream. We need to get going with cake. And then
freezer. That's the first one of those done. All right, come
on. 40 minutes. Get some fruit jam. I just need to get my
fridge for... That's not how it takes. It's nearly done. All
right, macaron. I've just done a middle layer with
strawberry mousse jam, and now I'm doing the final layer.
Just swapping the tears. So how long do we have left? Fakers,
you only have half an hour left. I'm happy with that. Right.
Oh, yeah, joking, mate. Lisa does basically peel off
perfectly. Come on, you stupid finger. Oh, you're f***ing
cracking. Let's see how much I learnt from Lara's art
lesson. Look a bit underdone, actually. Too soft. I just
don't think I've probably made the battle well enough, to be
honest, but deal with it. I need to just cut before for a
second, I think. Number two. Lara said you have to build up
the colour. Be patient. You can always go in the same
direction. You OK? No. You need it all to get smooth today,
though. Yeah. Dig deep. You can do this. I can do it. Where did
you get this design from? It's kind of like... I'm not very
good at doing it any other way. Nobody works there. It looks
really arty, doesn't it? This is going to be spring at the
top. I've got a two-sit and a potoclo. It's just going to look
very rushed, this. Bakers, you have 15 minutes left. Come
on. Don't swear, Dan. Come on. We're getting to kind of like
the critical point where I need to stack it. Don't want it to
lean. Dog's dinner. I want to put the greenhouse on now, and
then I can finish any time I've got spare. I'll just do some
decoration. How long's left? Looking good, bakers. You
have 10 minutes left. I'm going to have to rush a lot of
decoration there. I need a blowtorch. I don't know why I'm in
the bobbering. Goadly f***ing have it. These are my giant
marrows that I'd harvest in the autumn. I'll hide it with a
macaron pool. I'm true. We'll never know it. I want to do some
piping around the outside of it just to make it look a little
bit fancier. I've got a laugh now. One minute left. It's
messy. It's messy. Don't look behind you and look at Josh's
whatever you do. Bakers, your time is now up. Walk away
rapidly. Please step away from your bakes. We love you. Well
done. Thank you, then. Come on, go on. I don't worry about it.
Oh, no, my mistake. You've got four minutes left. The winner
of this year's bake-off will be announced at a very special
garden party in front of the baker's families and some old
friends. I'm back at the tent. It's so exciting. Just like
when we family all together again. We've got like a group
chat and we all talk on there and post pictures of what we've
been doing. And that's really lovely. It's so nice to be here
and not be baking and just feel like you can enjoy all the
wonderful cakes and that that have been made. In my mind, I
think Dan's going to win. But I think he's going to be so
close. I think we're all incredible. We're all good at
different things. I literally can't call it. If I had to say
something, maybe Josh, either Dan, or Josh, or Matty. One of
those. I think Matty could surprise everyone. It's
probably like asking a parent to pick their favourite
child. It's a very difficult call, Josh. Dan, for one last
time, bring up your showstopper. Dan, tell us all about your
final showstopper. So this is my lemon, drizzle and
meringue cake with a lemon curd and raspberry compote
topped with Italian meringue and decorated with some
macarons filled with the lemon curd and raspberry compote.
I quite like the white chocolate against the raspberry. I
like the meringue as well. Those macarons are terrible. I
know, I don't know what's going on with them. I wouldn't even
bother putting them on. Because it sort of ruins it. I did
think it was quite ambitious to do three chocolate collars.
It's cracked quite a bit. Yeah. Looks a lovely sponge there.
Doesn't it? Doesn't it? You know, it needs more lemon. The
drizzle only comes into so far, and then it stops, so... Ah,
OK. But the flavour is delicious, and I think the bake is
lovely as well. Macarons let it down dramatically. Yeah.
And the bake's not right either. No, I don't know what's gone
on. It's really pasty. Is it? Have I not cooked them flung
enough? No, you've definitely not cooked them flung
enough. No, not ever. No. It's just a little bit flawed for
me. Work to be done for next week, then. LAUGHTER Thanks,
really. Thanks very much. Matty, would you like to bring up
your share stopper, please? Matty, tell us about your share
stopper. The top and bottom tier are inspired by a chocolate
cake. So, it's a chocolate genoise sponge with a French
chocolate buttercream and chocolate brownie coated in a
Swiss meringue buttercream. The middle tier is a Victoria
sponge. So, it's lemon and rosemary with summerfruit jam
and an American buttercream. It's leaning a bit. The
dramatic effect. What happened, then? I mustn't have done
much of a job with the dows. I must say, Matty, I love the
colour combinations and the way you've done it. I like the
decoration, I like the piping, I like the fruit, the drop for
me is the big problem. Yeah, it's done me. But let's have a
look at what it's like inside. Wow, that's one light sponge.
Wow! I don't know, that looks beautiful, doesn't it? I mean,
I'm surprised it weighs enough to cause the lean. What a
great cake. Thank you. Now you're getting the chocolate
coming out. It's a really light, chocolaty, moorish
sponge. It's absolutely delicious. I have no good reason to
having another bite than I got to. I love the jam. I like the
cake. It reminds me of some of the nice, birthday cakes I had
when I was a kid. That's a beautiful sponge. All the flavours
are perfect. Thank you. Really perfect, Matty. You know
what? There's nothing wrong with this cake, except it's on
the lean. That's such a pity, because it's only one mistake.
Yeah. Everything else is absolutely perfect. Thank you,
Matty. Thank you very much. Well done, Matty, lad. Awesome.
Well done, mate. Good luck, mate. Josh did hang it off the
table. I think we'll be OK. We'll see. Josh, it's time for
your show, stopper. Josh, tell us all about your final show,
stopper. So, I've called this show stopper a slice for all
seasons. So, it's all representing the seasons in the
garden. It's always inspired by a Victoria sandwich. So,
the bottom tier is an apple and lemon sponge with a lemon curd
and a white chocolate buttercream. And the top two tiers are
the same. They're an apple and vanilla sponge with a
strawberry barbed jam and a white chocolate buttercream in
it as well. And it's all got Swiss meringue buttercream
around the outside and my biscuit greenhouse on top. I think
the greenhouse is great, and I think the colours are
beautiful. It is straight and it is level. The pipework is
not very neat. You could have spent another half hour on that
to create a much more polished image. Do you want to keep this
intact or can I taste the biscuit? You can taste it if you
want. There's some strawberry in the biscuit and they're
minced, used for the panels. Very clever, Dan. There's a
sugar biscuit in it. Yeah, just, yeah, about bound together
with some... Really minty, isn't it? It is minty. It is
minty. Thank you. Oh, you like that. Well, let's have a look
and see if we can try this spring. Mmm. Jam is perfect. I like
the sponge. I'm not getting any apple. It hasn't showed up to
the party. No, you can't taste the apple. No. You've gone
with the rhubarb and strawberry on this one. It needs
something more. OK. This one's got a little compressed with
the weight of the others. Yeah, thanks. Lovely lemon curd.
The lemon curd's nice. It's got a nice flavour. I think you
need another layer of lemon curd. I question whether that
sponge is actually overbaked as well. I think your flavours
are adequate and for me, I wanted to see much more of your
journey in the tent in that cake. I think boring is too strong
a word. But it's on its way. It's not your best shot. Thanks,
Josh. Thank you very much, Josh. MUSIC I think he was
probably being a bit harsher because I set my own standards
on my showtop. And I know that the finesse wasn't probably
quite there as I've, like, I don't know who's going to win. I
think it might be between me and Matty, maybe. Hopefully
I've done enough with yesterday as well, maybe. I've got
absolutely no idea to be honest. I don't feel like I'm going
to win it, so I think it's between them two personally.
Blimey. That could be enough. CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
CHEERING Hello, you. Come here. Whilst the bakers are
reunited with their families, crew and Paul have a huge
decision to make. That's it. We've done the last
showstopper. Pretty good cake. Just eat your fingers in all
of them, maybe. All right, Sammy. You guys were always
telling Dan to simplify. Today he definitely did simplify,
but he didn't get all the elements right. But with Josh,
you've never told him to simplify, and usually his
showstoppers are a bit more clever. I don't think that the
decoration was defined enough, and it wasn't up to his usual
standard. But he's still in line for winning, because he had
a good day yesterday. Yeah, he did. And I think Matty is also
pushed himself into that possibility of winning as well
because of what he's done today and because of his flavours.
The only thing that was wrong was Matty's. It was on the wonk.
It was on the wonk. But then you look at yesterday, in the
signature, they were very close. Josh won the technical.
Josh won Matty's third in the technical. Matty was bottom.
Technical yesterday was really good. Really pleased with
that. It is tight. I wouldn't want to be in your shoes. I want a
cup of tea and another slice. OK. Can I be the person who
actually announced the winner? That's all I want. You
should do it, because it's probably your last year. You
feeling Matty all right, mate? Yeah, I just need another
one, obviously. I'm getting my way as well. First, we'd like
to thank everyone for coming on this beautiful sunny day.
And I'd like to invite up the free finalists. Round of
applause for Dan. APPLAUSE Josh and Matty. Obviously, we'd
want every single one of you to win, but there can only be one
winner. So, it gives me great pleasure to announce that the
winner of the Great British Bake Off 2023 goes to... Matty!
CHEERING Here's to you, Charlie. Well done. Thank you. Well
done, mate. Well done. Thank you, mate. Good job. Good job,
Matty. You won, mate. Thank you. I don't know what to say. I
don't know what to say. APPLAUSE Oh, no! People say you
should go on Bake Off, and I just thought it was like a
throwaway comment. Never really listened to it. I never
thought that I would be on this. Let alone win it. We're all
going to put this... I can't even have it on show for a while,
can I? Well done! Oh, my God! So, trust from Matty. When it
always comes to the casing thing, he has been fantastic, so
he's such a worthy winner, and he's such a lovely chap as
well. You're only the winner? How amazing is that? He was
going home six times. I had a feeling Matty was going to win.
He's done it on the date, counted, and I am honestly so happy
for him. What a kid. I absolutely love him. I've never met a
more cheerful, smiling, uncomplaining and willing baker.
He just was having a good time, learning as much as he could,
taking on board everything either of us said. And he's just
got better and better and better. And if you're going to
smash it, you do it in the last challenge. And that's exactly
what he did. That chocolate cake was one of the best
chocolate cakes I've had for a long, long time. Lara. Lara, I
need you. There's been so many ups, there's been so many
downs, there's been so many times where I've had to been
pulled through by the people closest around me. Certainly
Lara. I can't imagine I've been too fun to live with in the
last ten weeks. I'm happy for them as much as I am for me with
this one. It still doesn't really feel real. I don't know, I
don't really know. What do you think it was that got you near?
Lara. Look at him. Oh, God, sorry. Oh, God. We don't notice
any time pass. We don't notice anything. We sit side by side
in every class. Teacher thinks that I sound funny, but she
likes the way you sing. Tonight I'll dream while I'm in bed
when silly thoughts go through my head. About the bugs and
alphabet. When I wake tomorrow I'll bet that you and I will
walk together again. I can tell that we are going to be
friends. I can tell that we are going to be friends. Bye. Are
you a star baker in the making? If you'd like to apply for the
next series of Bake Off, visit Channel 4.com forward slash
take part.