[Silence]
READY. READY. In the end, Charlie's mango entremets sent
him home. Spakers remain as they compete for the coveted
Great Chocolate Showdown title. This is not good. Just
start again. We are the last six Spakers. I cannot believe I
even made it this far and I am so excited. Hello, bakers! Hi!
Each of you has made incredible strides on your path to
becoming better bakers. But we're here to sweeten your
skills. It's time for your next technique test. Bakers, in
today's technique test, I'm going to show you how to make a
staple in the dessert world. The meringue. Oh, okay. There
are many delectable ways to marry chocolate and meringue.
I'm going to show you Italian meringue because it's the most
stable. Here's a tip for you bakers. Room temperature egg
whites whip up much better than cold ones. I'm adding some
cream of tartar which will help stabilize the meringue and
gives it a flexible, bouncy texture. Now I'm going to start
whipping my egg whites at a lower speed. Whipping at a lower
speed helps for air bubbles which will make the meringue
more stable. I want to get my egg whites to soft peak before I
add my sugar syrup, which I need to get to a temperature of 240
degrees Fahrenheit. Once it's up to temperature, I have to
slowly pour it into my sugar syrup. So now I'm going to show
you how to add color to your meringue. I'm using liquid food
gel color because it's highly concentrated. Chef Cynthia
looks so elegant while she shows us how to make meringues.
But there is no way that I'm going to look like Chef Cynthia.
I'm going to look at how it makes most likely. And now comes
the best part, piping it. First, throws. Next, a two-tone
star drop. Now this may look like a plain white meringue, but
looks can be deceiving because I've painted the inside of
the piping tip with food coloring. And this is going to
create a striped effect. Now you can pipe meringue directly
onto your parchment paper or you can also pipe it onto
skewers which will give height to your dessert. I'm piping
onto the dull end of my skewer so that the pointy end can be
inserted easily into a cake or a showpiece. Now that my
meringue is piped, I'm ready to bake it. And I bake my
meringues at 250 degrees Fahrenheit. Familiar with is
lemon meringue pie that my mom used to make. So I hope this is
something that I could do. My meringues are out of the oven
and cooled. Now it's time to decorate. I've painted my cone
form with white chocolate and I have some tempered
chocolate here to attach my meringue to my structure. Once
I've added all my meringues, I'll have something that looks
like this. Wow. Beautiful. For your next technique test,
you must create a themed meringue tower and six mini
desserts featuring meringue and chocolate. Oh, Christmas
tree. The piping possibilities and color choices are
endless. So we want to see a multi-colored and
multi-textured masterpiece. We expect amazing meringue
towers. So we're giving you a little extra baking power.
You're working in pairs. In order to find out who you'll be
working with, please choose the chocolate bar. Emma,
you're up first. Purple. Teal. Purple. I am so happy that me
and Emma are a pair because she decorates amazing and I have
the flavors. So this would be a great duo. Kristin, you're
next. I have pink. Mike. I chose teal. This is great. Tim and I
are going to make a really strong team. That means, Allie,
you'll be working with Kristin. I agree. Allie's precision
and Mike create eight of skills. That's going to make a great
team. Baker's Sweet Safety is in a table. From this point on,
all of you will bake in the Chocolate Elimination
Challenge. And the winning team of this technique test will
receive a special advantage in the Next Elimination
Challenge. The pantry is fully stocked with the finest
chocolate and ingredients. And you'll have two hours and 45
minutes to complete this test. Ready? Steady? Get your
sweet on. What should we call our theme? Pastel Princess
Dream. Ashley and I decide to do a pastel princess dream
theme because we love the colors of pastel and they match our
shirts. It's going to be cool. We got this. Our theme is the
rainbow candy shop. It looks so pretty. Kristin and I decide
to make a rainbow candy shop meringue tower because we love
rainbow colors. We got this. We do got this. Okay, I said we
make a peach themed cone and then a peach themed dessert so
it's really cohesive. Our theme is Life's a Peach because
Tim currently lives in Atlanta and I used to live in Atlanta
and Atlanta and the state of Georgia. Let's go. Let's go. We
got this. Merengues are so fun and they pair so well with
chocolate. And in terms of making a meringue that will hold
its shape, volume and color you need to be able to learn how to
read the meringue in the mixer. And you can tell when it's
whipped because it's glossy and shiny and holds a stiff
peak. Fast and smart. Fast and smart. So for this technique
test we're making six minute white chocolate peach décois
with a peach compote and a graham cracker and pecan crumble.
But the first thing that we start on is our meringue. As I
start my meringue I start by separating my egg whites and if
you get any yolk inside of these egg whites then it can throw
off the consistency of your meringue and it may not set.
How's it going over there? Good. I'm at 240 so you're such a
talented parer. I'm proud of you. For our mini desserts
we're going to make a chai spice macaron with a Swiss
meringue buttercream and a milk chocolate ganache. And we
are good. My meringue mixture is at the right peaks that it
needs to be. I'm feeling very good about this before. I'm
just going to whip a little bit more and then they'll be
ready. How's it going Ashley? You good? I'm good. Okay. For
our mini desserts we're making pavlovo filled with milk
chocolate pastry cream and fresh fruits. Watch your eggs.
You don't want to over whip. Oh yeah, yeah. We are both going
at such a fast pace and I'm really glad that we're on the same
page. All right I'm starting on another batch. Yeah me too.
Get those things whipped up. So silky. Now it's time to color
the meringues and I'm going to start off with pink. My
favorite color. Is this pink online? Love it. Are you happy
with your color over there? Alrighty. One of the pitfalls
our bakers can run into is in working in their color that
they're over folding. So with every fold you are deflating
that meringue a little bit and then if you fold too much when
those meringues hit the heat of the oven they'll start
breaking down and then they become too fragile and crumbly.
We're doing good. We're doing good. Okay I'm going to start
working on the peach color jab. Okay. I'm making sure that we
have a variation of color for our peach themed tower from a
deeper darker peachy red to almost a yellow tone. Yeah I like
that. Yeah right? I like it a lot. The goal is piping out
different shapes colors. Oh these are cool looking man.
Also you have meringue in your beard right now. I thought it
made me look distinguished. Trying not to be so messy but I
gotta speed it up. As I'm working on the larger meringues,
Allie is working on the smaller ones. Hey Allie how's your
piping going over there? Pretty good. I'm feeling really
good about these meringues. They are looking wonderful and
vibrant. It's going to be so good. Now all the teams have
their meringues in the oven so our bakers really don't need
to stop working on their desserts. I am starting on the
shells for our macaron. It's my first time actually popping
this. It's not to be too sloppy with them. I've never made
macarons before so I hope these come out right. Oh that looks
awesome. I'm going to go ahead and start on the peach
compote. Okay I'm going to start tempering chocolate.
Perfect. So now I'm moving on to tempering chocolate. This
tempered chocolate is going to be the glue that's going to
allow us to put our meringues onto this comb. Another
chocolate coming along. It is taking it sweet time. Alright
we got to get to hopefully decorating by a one hour mark. Yeah
this chocolate is taking forever to come to temper. Bakers
one hour left. I'm frustrated because if I can't get this
chocolate tempered enough time to put our tower together.
Come on. Can't make this cool any faster. I know I'm
tempering the chocolate correctly but I'm wondering if
maybe I'm making a little bit too much which is why it's
taking so long. So I take some of the white chocolate out and
put it into another bowl and that chocolate I'll use to cover
the comb. Okay this is ready to paint the comb if you want to
take it. Finally after what feels like forever our white
chocolate is being tempered. This tempered chocolate is
going to be the glue that's going to allow us to put our
meringues onto this comb. Yes sir. We got this. For this
technique test we have to mix six mini meringue desserts and
a meringue tower. My vision for the top of our tower is to make
a big pastel lollipop. Perfect for a princess. I finished
doing my meringues. My macarons are set. Now it's time to
coat the base of the tower. Looks really good Christian.
Thanks. Okay I am ready to start putting stuff on. Miss
tempered chocolate that took forever is working in peace to
the tower itself. Looks like a traffic cone. 30 minutes. We
got everything done we just got a symbol. Yes. Just do it.
Just to get them all make them look good. Life's a peach.
Life's a peach. Bakers 15 minutes left on the clock. Alright
y'all keep going. Keep on hustling. At this point I'm
sticking them anywhere. Oh because the malls are good. It's
getting there. You got this. Come on baking. Oh my freaking
gosh. 10, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 time's up. Did that girl. Yeah.
I'm really looking forward to the judges tasting this
dessert and know the flavors there and I know they're going
to be wowed by it. Oh my god how bad you know. It looks pretty
good. Snaps for the rainbow candy shop. Bakers in teams of
two we asked you to create a themed meringue tower and six
mini meringue based desserts. Christian, Allie. Yeah.
Allie and I created a rainbow candy shop thing meringue
tower with a chai spice macaron and a Swiss meringue
buttercream and a milk chocolate ganache. Well this is a
kaleidoscope of color and texture. You've done some
fantastic piping work. Your meringues are well executed
but I wish you hadn't have gone for the luster spray because
my favorite color scheme on this tower is this patch get two
with the luster spray. Look at that vibrance and then over
here where the blueish luster spray got to it, it mutes all
the colors. They look perfect. Allie, Kristen, I love your
macaron for the first time ever making it. Get over here.
Chefs practice their whole life and they can't get it. Thank
you. Your milk chocolate ganache melts in my mouth at that
punch of chocolate. Your chai Swiss buttercream it balance
so well with your chocolate ganache. Nice work. I'm so proud
of you. I am so stoked. Go Allie, go Kristen. Mike, Tim,
please bring us your meringue tower. Our meringue tower is
named Life's A Peach. We made a white chocolate peach de
quoi. There is a peach compote and a graham cracker pecan
crumble. Well, I really like that you did a lot of unique
different piping techniques, different color schemes,
but your desserts, they look roughly assembled and your
meringue shells. A daquoise is a meringue that has ground
nuts stirred into it and then baked and then that is layered
with your creams and your fillings. So did you stir any nuts
into that meringue? No, we did not. Shall we give it a taste?
Yes. Mike, Tim, I can certainly see the nod to peaches, but I
can see some of your swirls have started to collapse on each
other and that's just because some of the volume from your
meringue was lost. Chocolate work. If you go to that much
work to make a leaf like that, I want to see more. But when it
comes down to the desserts, the flavor of the peaches with
the graham and the pecans and the cinnamon, it just has that
wonderful comfort food feel, but had it been presented as an
elegant dessert, would have blown my mind. Thank you. Thank
you. I'm most nervous about the judges' critique about the
appearance, but they absolutely love the way the dessert
tastes, so I hope that's going to make up for it. Emma and
Ashley, you're up. Our theme of this meringue tower is
pastel princess dream. And we made six peplovers with milk
chocolate, pastry cream and fresh fruit. Ashley and Emma,
wow, this truly is a meringue tower fit for a princess. And of
course, you were very smart and painted your cone along the
same tones, which helps unify the look. I love that you added
a top things the whole thing together. Okay, shall we give
these a try? Yeah, please. Your milk chocolate pastry cream
was on point. It wasn't overly sweet, which was good because
with the meringue being sweet, it would have been too
intense, but your desserts are inconsistent, so you got to
make sure every single one is the same. I have to flag one
concern of mine. Your dessert is prepared from the exact
same meringue that you used to create the tower. A meringue
and a pavlova is intended to be crispy all the way through. A
pavlova should be crunchy on the outside, soft in the
center, and two ingredients are added to the meringue,
cornstarch and lemon juice. This is actually a meringue
nest. Thank you. Thank you. BAKERS, congratulations. All
of you delivered delightful and playful showpieces. But
there was one team who created a meringue tower that was a
vibrant, multi-textured masterpiece. Alongs two.
BAKERS, there was one team who created a meringue tower that
was a multi-textured masterpiece. And that tower belongs
to... Kristen and Allie. Thank you. Your rainbow candy shop
was a technicolor triumph. And that macaron at the end of the
rainbow was a tasty little treasure. A special advantage in
the next challenge. Mmm, yeah. BAKERS, all of you have come a
long way in the skills you've shown us. And you've also come a
long way to be here in this kitchen. We know you must miss
home. So we have a postcard from someone who misses you too.
Oh, my daughter! It's from my mom. It's from my sister, my
husband and my third son, Clay. It's from my grandmother.
And she says, Hi, Kristen. I'm sitting here thinking about
you and how much I miss you. I love you so much and so proud of
you. My daughter, Janayia, says congratulations, mommy,
on making it this far. Hang in there, you're making me so
proud. Your hard work does not go unnoticed. Never give up.
Words cannot express how proud I am of you. I know that Dad and
Patrick are cheering you on from above. You are a rising
star, something so important and being visible for
Indigenous women. I love you so much and so proud of you. I
know you can do it. Dear Daddy, we miss you and care for you. We
are cheering for you to win $50,000. I miss you so much and I'm
rooting you on. Your biggest cheerleader, love mom. Love
Janayia. Love grandmother. I'm good. I love you from Clay.
He's an amazing kid. He's very unique. I don't even know the
last time I cried. We have a bunch of softies in here. We hope
your postcards provide a bit of comfort and some sweet
motivation for your next bake. Desserts have the power to
take us on amazing journeys from a trip back home to a faraway
place we've only dreamed about. For your next chocolate
elimination challenge, you are going on a flavorful
adventure. We want you to create a plated chocolate dessert
highlighting an ingredient from our international
pantry. Okay. On your postcards, you will find a number that
matches a number on the cupboard. Who's got number one?
That'd be me. Tip. Blue corn. Kristen. I have wattle seed.
Mike. I have add Zuki Beans. Number four. I got Sumac. Number
five. Black Sesame Paste. Last but not least, Ashley. I got
Tiger Nuts. Kristin and Allie, ask the winners of the
technique test. You will each receive some judge advice
once during your bake. A ring of bell. And ask for one of us to
help you with some expert tips for success. The pantry is
fully stocked with the finest chocolate and ingredients,
and you'll have two and a half hours to complete this
challenge. The baker who presents us with our least
favorite dessert will be going home. Ready? Steady? Get
your chocolate on. Let's go. I think after receiving these
postcards, everyone wants to put their best foot forward.
Seem to be threatened. We're taking off with this
challenge. We don't want to just see the ingredients
sprinkled on top. We want to be able to taste those flavors.
So they need to play with the ingredient and discover does it
need to be steeped into a liquid? Does it need to be heated? So
they really have to step up their gate. Tiger Nuts originate
from North Africa and not actually nuts with small root
vegetables with a sweet nutty flavor similar to coconut. I
already know a little bit about Tiger Nuts. My best friend's
husband is from Africa and he makes Tiger Nut pudding. So I'm
making a Tiger Nut, and I'm going to substitute the almond
for the Tiger Nut. I'm going to have a chocolate Tiger Nut
base of vanilla custard, and I'm going to have chocolate on
the top. And I'm also making a Tiger Nut brittle. I put it in my
food processor to blend them. Not working. How long are they
chopping up? The Tiger Nuts are too hard. I have to boil these
nuts so I can blend them up. Or I'm just not going to be able to
give the judges anything. And I want to make my daughter
Janaya so proud of me. I boil my Tiger Nuts, take them out, and
I start to blend them. Finally. Azuki beans are commonly
used in East Asian desserts flavor. I am making a matcha and
azuki bean whipped cream roulade with a milk chocolate
ganache, matcha crumble, some azuki bean jellies, and a
dark chocolate sauce. I cannot use the azuki beans the way
that they are. No one wants to bite into a whole bean. So I'm
going to put them in the food processor and blend them down
really finely. And then I'm going to add some sugar to the
azuki bean paste and heat them together to bring out the
azuki bean flavor while also adding a lot of sweetness. Mmm.
That is much better with a lot of sugar in it. I know my dad and
my husband are cheering me on from above. So I'm going to give
it my best. Flavor with hints of coffee and hazelnut. I'm
making a wattle seed pina cotta and a chocolate hazelnut
shortbread with a chocolate wattle seed espresso sauce and
a caramelized hazelnut crumble. First, I'm going to get
started on my wattle seed pina cotta and I boil my wattle seed
with the cream and sugar so it can absorb the flavor. And I put
it in the fridge to set. Boop-boop-boop. Next, I put my
chocolate hazelnut wattle seed shortbread on a baking
tray. Oh, yeah. This is fine. Okay. I'm making a milk
chocolate black sesame mochi filled with black sesame milk
chocolate ganache with black sesame sablé and a strawberry
gelet. The black sesame flavor is really nutty and rich, so
the strawberries are going to bring a sweetness to it. I'm
making mochi because mochi is traditionally a Japanese
dessert and black sesame paste is also from Japan, so I think
the two pair well together. I think many people are familiar
with toasted sesame oil, but black sesame paste has an even
more pronounced sesame flavor, which means a nuttiness,
almost a smokiness. And I think the fact that Emma is using
milk chocolate will pair well with the sesame. I'm doing
donuts. Yum. I'm going to be making a blue corn chocolate
donut, but I'm going to elevate it with a rose water and
raspberry coulis, a cardamom, diplomat cream, and a blue
corn lace twill, and pistachio crumble. I'm going into this
challenge after receiving this postcard more focused than
ever. It made me start thinking about not just Clay, but my
other two kids, my wife. I know they're all rooting for me.
Now it's time to bake. Sumac is a spice that has a citrus-like
quality and can also be used to add a pop of color to a dish. I am
making a milk chocolate vertical sumac tart. That's not
fancy. I am literally standing a tart up on its side. There's
no backing to it at all, and there's going to be sumac milk
chocolate ganache, a sumac caramel sauce, milk chocolate
mousse, and a white chocolate tempered garnish. And
hopefully the judges love that. Kristen and I got this
advantage, and it's a huge deal. If at any point we get stuck,
we can ring the bell and get help. We'll see how this goes.
Elise is my shortbread. Smells delicious. So now I'm going
to check on my Waddle Sea Pina Cotta. Doesn't look like it's
setting correctly. Oh, goodness. It's like half set at the
bottom, but not so much at the top. This is not good. Bakers,
one hour left. Oh, goodness. I'm nervous that my panna cotta
is not going to be set in time, so I think I'm going to use this
bell for some advice. Chef Anna, I need your help. I'll be
right there. Kristen. Can we check my panna cotta? Yes,
please. Oh, your gelatin is not dissolved in it. So what
should I do? I think you're better off just start again.
Starting over? Yeah. Blune the gelatin, make sure it gets
fully melted in that cream. Mm-hmm. Put it in a flutter dish,
and then it'll chill faster. OK. I'm running out of time, but
when Chef Anna tells you to start something over, you do it.
On to the next step. For this chocolate elimination
challenge, we must have a plate of dessert that highlights
an ingredient from the international pantry. I'm going to
do the filling for my Nanaimo bar. I mix butter, powdered
sugar, vanilla, and heavy cream. Pale like yellow, I know
that it's already. There needs to whip because it needs to
change in color. At the same time, I'm making my tiger nut
brutal. Ooh, my glasses. Glasses keep fogging up. This is
going to be a great brutal. Ooh, it smells so good. My cake is
cooling, so I am going to incorporate my azuki bean paste
into a cream filling. I'm also going to make a jelly out of the
bean because it should also enhance the azuki bean flavor.
I'm also going to make a milk chocolate ganache to go with it
because the judges always like to see more chocolate. These
are my strawberry gelet, and they look pretty good to me. And
now it's time to make my mochi. To make the mochi, I mix
together fruit and rice flour, sugar, and water, and then
put that in the microwave and heat it up. The texture of mochi
is really sticky, and it kind of feels like modeling clay. I
flatten out the mochi dough and roll it in cornstarch and
make discs so that I can fill it with my black sesame ganache.
I think that they will be a good texture. Now that my tart
dough is ready to go and my ganache is made, it's time to get
started on my sumac caramel sauce. It does not look right.
Oh, no, it's crystallized. That's not good. At this point, I
decide to ring my bell to get some input from Chef Steve
because if I don't get this caramel sauce on my plate, I will
only have one element of sumac, and that is not good. I'm
really having problems with my caramel. Okay, was your
cream hot when you added it or cold? Room temp. Room
temperature. Quick trick. First, warm your cream and your
sumac together. Bring it to a boil. Strain it. Then, when you
get that golden amber color, you pour your cream into your
sugar slowly whisking. Once that's done, take it off. Allow
it to most fire buttery. Okay, thank you. Good luck. Okay, I
can do this. I attempt to make my caramel sauce again, and
this is still not working. My caramel keeps crystallizing,
and crystallization in your caramel is a big no-no. So I'm
just gonna stick with my original batch. And even though it
doesn't look like caramel sauce, it still tastes great. You
have 30 minutes left! It's time for me to work on this blue
corn twill. Oh, okay. I see you're starting to do this little
thing thing. This is going to add a list occasion to this
plate. When you read the word, it looks like you're supposed
to go... Twills and twirls. Okay. I'm gonna attempt to roll
my cake. Before I roll the roulette, I need to make sure I, of
course, include the whipped cream that I've made that's got
the azuki bean in it, and then I also have my milk chocolate
ganache that needs to be spread as well. I'm nervous about
rolling this roulette, because the biggest danger when
making roulette is if the cake cracks. If it does, the
ingredients you put on the inside are gonna start seeping
out, and you're gonna lose that beautiful swirl effect that
you've worked so hard for. Okay, I am happy with how that
looks. Please look perfect, please look perfect, please
look perfect. After I punch out the ganache, it's time to put
it in the tart shell. And the tart shell breaks. Oh, it is so
fragile. I only have two tart shells left. So I have to be
really careful, because I have no room for error. Oh, my
gosh, I'm so nervous. Bakers, you have five minutes left.
All right, lots of details. All right, guys, keep going. Got
time, I got time, I got time. I'm gonna get it out. For a run to
the blast chiller, to check on my water sea penicato.
Penicato. Yo, yo, we got this. Looks so yummy. One minute
left, Bakers, let's go. Okay, Kers. Focus, focus, focus.
Almost there. Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one, time's up. Oh. Good job, everyone. I would
need that. This is the best dessert I've plated yet. This is
Daughter Janiah. Bakers, we asked you to create a plated
chocolate dessert featuring an ingredient from our
international pantry. Tim, please bring us your dessert.
I've made a blue corn chocolate donut with a rose water and
raspberry coulis. I am astounded at the plate you presented
us. It's so clean and neat. And you chose a donut which, of
course, I get the slight joke, given you're a profession as a
policeman, but that is not like any donut. You're going to
find a donut store. Let's give it a try. Well, Tim, I thought
your donut's texture was so dreamy. It had that airiness and
lightness and was very chocolatey, but you could
definitely taste the blue corn. I so very much wish that you
would give me that recipe. That balance between the rich
chocolate and the perfume of the blue corn, it takes over
your palate, but in a good way, that postcard from your son
Clay gave you just that drive you needed. Thank you, Jedis.
Kristen, please bring us your plate. I made a waddle-sea
panna cotta and a chocolate hazelnut shortbread. Kristen,
you have really smartened up your plating style. Thank you.
It is composed and it looks like your panna cotta set okay.
Shall we give this a taste? Mm-hmm. Kristen, your dessert's
waddle-seed featured so beautifully. It was definitely
the start of that plate. Your shortbread tasted great. The
only thing I did not like your panna cotta, it was too tart. It
needed a little more sugar. But you have presented a
cohesive, well-rounded, plated dessert. Thank goodness
for this advantage and Chef Emma, because I would not have a
dessert to present. Mike, please bring us your dessert. I
present to you a matcha and a zucca roulade with milk
chocolate ganache, a zuccy bean jellies, and a tempered
chocolate garnish. This is a beautiful plate. Thank you.
I'm feeling nervous. No matter how confident I've been in
any of the desserts that I've given the judges, they have
faces that are very hard to read when they're eating your
dessert. Mike, Mikey, Michael. Now I'm in trouble. Yeah,
yeah. Mike, beautifully beautiful presentation. I love
how you cut the roulade on a bias to give it height. You should
be very proud of yourself. Thank you. I got the a zuccy bean
flavor, but I got that more than the chocolate. I lost the
chocolate in every aspect of the dessert. The milk
chocolate was a little mild against that earthy intensity
of a zuccy. But what I am very proud of, Mike, is your plate
presentation, your thought process, and the composition
of what you've presented to us. Thank you so much. Allie,
please bring it. I created a milk chocolate vertical sumac
tart with a milk chocolate sumac ganache and a sumac caramel
sauce. Allie, absolutely gorgeous. Allie, your tart
shell, great crumb. It had a bite and a crunch and a flakiness
to it. That being said, you missed it on the caramel. You
didn't get that caramel there, and I couldn't taste the
sumac in it. If you have a tart that size and literally half a
teaspoon of caramel, you're not going to get that caramel in
every bite. Yeah. And I wanted more sumac. The real selling
feature of sumac is this sparkle of acidity. Yeah. So I
really wanted more of that. I am a little disappointed, but I
hope that my plating skills and presentation are enough to
keep me here. Ashley, please bring us your dessert. I made a
tiger nut, a tiger nut brittle, and a maple tiger nut
crumble. What you've given us is a wonderfully beautiful
plate. The elements on the plate make sense, and this is a big
step up for you. Ashley, I want to congratulate you on that.
Thank you. Time for a taste. Ashley, your Nanaimo bar, the
custard layer and the chocolate layer were both beautiful.
I did run into slight issues with the brittle. A plated
dessert is meant so you could have crumbled your brittle a
little bit so that it can fit neatly on a fork. But the way you
integrated the tiger nut into that Nanaimo bar base
particularly gave it such texture and body and flavor at the
same time partnered with that intense chocolate, the
ganache on top. It was sublime. Thank you. So obviously
getting that postcard did something. It's lit a fire in you.
I can see that. I believe strongly. Your daughter is nothing
but proud of you. And we're super. Emma, please bring us your
dessert. I made a milk chocolate black sesame mochi filled
with black sesame milk chocolate ganache as well as a black
sesame chocolate salble. You are plating, I think it's
original and creative, and the mochi has got that clarity to
it. So you can see that dark intense sesame filling hiding
underneath. I can't wait to jump in. Emma, in giving us the
flavor of your black sesame paste, I think it was there. More
pronounced in the mochi than the salble. The chocolate
dominated the salble. So the two together in one bite were
equally balanced. But eating your mochi bowl, the filling
inside was a little bit too thick. So it was quite hard to
break into, and it's normally meant to be very smooth. And
your mochi itself too glutinous. It was really elastic. So I
think you need to refine your technique there. Thank you.
I'm really getting worried that I might be going home today.
Bakers, we asked for a plated chocolate dessert featuring
an ingredient from our global pantry. Some of you took us on
exciting voyages filled with irresistible flavors and
innovative plates. But sadly, not everyone's dessert had
the impact we were hoping for. When I call your name, please
step forward. Mike. Mike. And... Both of you are safe. Tim
and Ashley, please step forward. The two of you had our
favorite desserts of this challenge. Thank you. But who had
the best dessert? Congratulations, Ashley. I'm so
excited. My daughter will be so proud of me. Ashley, your
tiger nut and enymo bar had ferocious flavor. We heard your
roar of determination in this challenge. Keep it up. Thank
you. Thank you. Emma and Ali, unfortunately, your desserts
were not as successful. Ali, we have come to expect elegant
plates from you, which is exactly what you gave vertical
tart. It was striking. However, in a dessert where sumac was
meant to be showcased, it felt like an afterthought. Emma,
we thought your plating was charming, and you definitely
featured black sesame paste throughout your dessert.
Sadly, we found your mochi chewy and your sablée dry.
Unfortunately, one of you must leave this kitchen. The
baker who is going home is... Ali. Ali, you are an incredibly
talented baker with an artist's touch. You've shown us an
impressive array of techniques, and we know your baking is
going to become nothing short of exceptional. This whole
experience has been so incredible, and I'm so excited to be
able to share my message and my story to everyone out there.
Indigenous people need to be seen and heard, and I helped
take a little step forward for my own work. I love my people,
and I love that. Grateful for all of the knowledge I've
gotten. It's only going to help me become a better baker.
This is just the beginning. Wow. Next time on Great
Chocolate Showdown... Let's get ready to crumble! ...the
final five bakers tackle dessert sandwiches...
Delicious. ...from bread rolls to starring rolls... Come
get your popcorn! The bakers are cast in a blockbuster
elimination challenge. Let's do this. Drama unfolds in
their most epic bake-y-est. Chocolate background player
in your desserts again. You